<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sync on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/sync/</link><description>Recent content in sync on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 10:16:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/sync/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running gcp.py from cron</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/03/running-gcp-py-from-cron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 10:16:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/03/running-gcp-py-from-cron/</guid><description>On my backup server I run gcp.py from gdatacopier to backup my google docs. I had to fix two issues in order to get it to run from a bash script:
the PYTHONPATH had to be exported prior to running, or the script will fail because it requires gdata-python-client the LANG envronment has to be set otherwise it will spill the following error in the log (if you bother to log the output from cron that is, otherwise it will just not work and you won&amp;rsquo;t know why, because the script works fine when ran manually) Traceback (most recent call last): File &amp;#34;/usr/local/bin/gcp.</description></item><item><title>Automatically sync photos from digikam to your mobile phone</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/22/automatically-sync-photos-from-digikam-to-your-mobile-phone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 08:10:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/22/automatically-sync-photos-from-digikam-to-your-mobile-phone/</guid><description>I shoot a lot of pictures. My collection keeps growing (for example ~90 Gb right now) and since last year I discovered the joy of using digikam to tag and organize them. I&amp;rsquo;m using the beta 2.0.0 version and use mysql to store it&amp;rsquo;s databases (as opposed to the default sqlite) as it&amp;rsquo;s easier to interact and backup. What I want is to carry some of those pictures with me, specifically on my phone.</description></item><item><title>How I sync my phone</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/25/how-i-sync-my-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 08:17:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/25/how-i-sync-my-phone/</guid><description>Like I said I used to have an Sony Ericsson phone that had Automatic Sync built in. Nokia has sync (SyncML) but no settings to automate that. I like the ideea of syncing a phone with an online service because it gives me access to my schedule and contacts on any pc I use without the need of additional software.
Some time ago I tried goosync, Scheduleworld and others promissing easy sync between a SyncML capable device (my phone) and Google Calendar.</description></item><item><title>Take your mobile phone for a "Swim"</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/take-your-mobile-phone-for-a-swim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 08:08:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/take-your-mobile-phone-for-a-swim/</guid><description>At one point I&amp;rsquo;ve been the shamed user of a Sony Ericsson v610i. Pretty simple candybar phone. Although it had one function that put my next phone (the Nokia E61) and my current phone to shame. It had syncml capabilities with the option of automatic, periodic syncing. Guess what&amp;hellip; the flagship E series device of its time didn&amp;rsquo;t!
Open source to the rescue. I searched for a sollution for some time, eventually giving up, until I discovered, recently the Bergamot Project with its Swim project.</description></item></channel></rss>