<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>e71 on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/e71/</link><description>Recent content in e71 on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 17:00:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/e71/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Three browsers on a phone</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/01/three-browsers-on-a-phone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 17:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/01/three-browsers-on-a-phone/</guid><description>The current state of browsers available for the Symbian operating system are a proof that there isn&amp;rsquo;t such thing as a one size fits all._ ****_You have the default browser, opera mobile, opera mini, skyfire and some others. I have installed on my e71 nokia phone Opera Mobile 10 beta, Skyfire and of course the default browser.
I tried to settle on using just one but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t. If I want to watch some flash video online or browse a really heavy site Skyfire is really the only option.</description></item><item><title>I found the best themes for my E71</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/20/i-found-the-best-themes-for-my-e71/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 13:26:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/20/i-found-the-best-themes-for-my-e71/</guid><description>I gave up finding a nice theme for my E71 long ago. Even accepted the ugly icons. A few weeks ago I found a decent theme with ovi icons and got a bit happier. Today I had time to search a bit some more and I have some of the best Nokia E71 themes I found:
Ovi Blue from Nokia Conversations
Aviator, Enterprise and Zen Touch from Tehkseven - those are both with sevan and ovi icons.</description></item><item><title>Smart connect update</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/10/smart-connect-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 15:53:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/10/smart-connect-update/</guid><description>Remeber my article in which I was praising Smart Connect for filling the inexplicable gap in the access point configuration on newer E series nokia phones?
Well I have a small update. It&amp;rsquo;s crap. From time to time my phone was unnable to connect to the internet, be it 3g or wi-fi untill I restarted it. I kept thinking it&amp;rsquo;s the phones problem, and waited for a firmware update. Well I managed to track the problem: it&amp;rsquo;s Smart Connect.</description></item><item><title>The quest for mobile Youtube is over</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/10/the-quest-for-mobile-youtube-is-over/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 15:44:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/10/the-quest-for-mobile-youtube-is-over/</guid><description>Ever since Flash 3.0 came out and I managed to install it on my Nokia E61 phone I have been using one or other mobile youtube application. It&amp;rsquo;s a handy app to have when you want to kill some time. I started with emTube which was pretty good, but never got updated and for me it stopped working.
Mobitubia saved the day, especially with it&amp;rsquo;s nice interface, ability to save files for later viewing and so on.</description></item><item><title>The best freeware weather application for my Nokia E71</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/03/the-best-freeware-weather-application-for-my-nokia-e71/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 17:14:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/03/the-best-freeware-weather-application-for-my-nokia-e71/</guid><description>&amp;hellip; or any symbian device for that matter - even s60v2 based devices.
I like having weather informations at hand. At home I have a nice mini weather station, but I still like to be able to check it on my phone. I tried a few apps before this one, even commercial ones like Handy Weather, still I find M!Weather - Mobile weather from the ubahnstation the best. [404 as of 2002] It&amp;rsquo;s fast, it&amp;rsquo;s free and it&amp;rsquo;s acurate.</description></item><item><title>Take your mobile phone for a "Swim"</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/take-your-mobile-phone-for-a-swim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 08:08:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/take-your-mobile-phone-for-a-swim/</guid><description>At one point I&amp;rsquo;ve been the shamed user of a Sony Ericsson v610i. Pretty simple candybar phone. Although it had one function that put my next phone (the Nokia E61) and my current phone to shame. It had syncml capabilities with the option of automatic, periodic syncing. Guess what&amp;hellip; the flagship E series device of its time didn&amp;rsquo;t!
Open source to the rescue. I searched for a sollution for some time, eventually giving up, until I discovered, recently the Bergamot Project with its Swim project.</description></item><item><title>What’s installed on my Nokia E71 and why.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/whats-installed-on-my-nokia-e71-and-why/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 09:37:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/whats-installed-on-my-nokia-e71-and-why/</guid><description>As you might have noticed I am very fond of open source or freeware software. I like the community and the development pace of such projects, and of course I am fond of the price. So, before watching another top 10 freeware list, here&amp;rsquo;s a list from someone who actually used the programs for months or years and uses them on a daily basis:
1. Home screen From left to right:</description></item><item><title>Access point groups on the Nokia 71</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/04/23/access-point-groups-on-the-nokia-71/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 14:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/04/23/access-point-groups-on-the-nokia-71/</guid><description>When I upgraded my phone from a venerable and branded Nokia E61 to a more modern Nokia E71 I quickly found out what most of the reviewers missed. The E71 has no Access Point Groups - one feature that I used a lot. I usually have just two groups - wifi_first and wifi_only - one for always connected apps (fring, email, etc) and the other for data intensive apps that I usually only use at home or at work (youtube, download and the like).</description></item></channel></rss>