<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 10:01:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Latest openssh disables arcfour and blowfish-cbc</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/21/latest-openssh-disables-arcfour-and-blowfish-cbc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 10:01:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/21/latest-openssh-disables-arcfour-and-blowfish-cbc/</guid><description>If you move a lot of data using rsync/scp/ssh you probably found out by now that arcfour or blowfish ciphers are a lot faster than others. A comparison is found in this thread. (TL;DR arcfou256 is the fastest cipher).
Today I updated openssh on my slackware servers only to be greeted by this error from scripts doing rsync to my backup server:
no matching cipher found: client arcfour server aes128-ctr,aes192-ctr,aes256-ctr,aes128-gcm@openssh.com,aes256-gcm@openssh.com,chacha20-poly1305@openssh.com rsync: connection unexpectedly closed (0 bytes received so far) [Receiver] rsync error: unexplained error (code 255) at io.</description></item><item><title>Yahoo Messenger Michael Jackson virus</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/19/yahoo-messenger-michael-jackson-virus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 09:59:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/19/yahoo-messenger-michael-jackson-virus/</guid><description>A friend of mine got infected via Yahoo Messenger. The virus, spreads via mass messaging the following message:
HAHA Michael Jackson Gay 😀 &amp;raquo; http://looool.machiaeljack**ndied.com
The link takes you to something that looks like a picture, but because the file name ends with what appears to the user as a web adress the final extension is .com not .jpg - and so you get tricked into running an executable.</description></item><item><title>What I add to a fresh install of Windows XP</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/01/what-i-add-to-a-fresh-install-of-windows-xp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 08:30:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/01/what-i-add-to-a-fresh-install-of-windows-xp/</guid><description>Yes, yes, I know, Windows 7 is all the rage today. But, XP is still widely used and for now is the operating system I need to install on 90% of the cases. Of course first I install Windows XP, then the pc&amp;rsquo;s drivers and utilities, then I add whatever commercial software the client uses. After that, from case to case I always add some of the following:
Security If it&amp;rsquo;s a home user that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a paid antivirus solution I install AVG free or Avast Home edition.</description></item></channel></rss>