<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>32bit on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/32bit/</link><description>Recent content in 32bit on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 13:05:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/32bit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>request_module: runaway loop modprobe binfmt-464c</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/07/request_module-runaway-loop-modprobe-binfmt-464c/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 13:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/07/request_module-runaway-loop-modprobe-binfmt-464c/</guid><description>I added a new disk to my HP N40L and moved the boot disk to another SATA port, which meant reconfiguring lilo. Strange enough after setting everything up I got:
request_module: runaway loop modprobe binfmt-464c right after the kernel loading.
Long story short this message means you are trying to boot a 32bit system with a 64 bit kernel (maybe the other way around will spit something similar). I set the boot parameter wrong and I was actually trying to boot and old 32 bit linux install that was still around on one of the drives in the NAS</description></item><item><title>Another issue compiling Digikam 2.0.0 stable on my Slackware current 64 bit (post 13.37)</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/08/20/another-issue-compiling-digikam-2-0-0-stable-on-my-slackware-current-64-bit-post-13-37/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2011 18:14:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/08/20/another-issue-compiling-digikam-2-0-0-stable-on-my-slackware-current-64-bit-post-13-37/</guid><description>This error is spit after compiling:
Linking CXX shared module ../../../lib/kipiplugin_advancedslideshow.so /usr/lib64/gcc/x86_64-slackware-linux/4.5.3/../../../../x86_64-slackware-linux/bin/ld: skipping incompatible /usr/share/opencv/../../lib/libGL.so when searching for -lGL collect2: ld returned 1 exit status make[2]: \*** [lib/kipiplugin_advancedslideshow.so] Error 1 make[1]: \*** [extra/kipi-plugins/advancedslideshow/CMakeFiles/kipiplugin_advancedslideshow.dir/all] Error 2 make: \*** [all] Error 2 For whatever reason it tries to use the 32 bit version of libGL.so from /usr/lib Since I was annoyed at this point so I simply renamed /usr/lib to /usr/lib.old and compiled digikam than reverted.</description></item><item><title>Memory limits of various Windows versions</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/memory-limits-of-various-windows-versions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 21:02:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/memory-limits-of-various-windows-versions/</guid><description> Thinking of a memory upgrade? An operating system upgrade? Here&amp;rsquo;s a table from msdn stating the limits imposed by 32 and 64 bit editions of various Windows versions.
Physical Memory Limits: Windows 7 The following table specifies the limits on physical memory for Windows 7.
Version Limit in 32-bit Windows Limit in 64-bit Windows Windows Server 2003 with Service Pack 2 (SP2), Datacenter Edition 128 GB 64 GB with 4GT 2 TB Windows Server 2003 with Service Pack 2 (SP2), Enterprise Edition 64 GB 2 TB Windows Storage Server 2003, Enterprise Edition 8 GB Not applicable Windows Storage Server 2003 4 GB Not applicable Windows Server 2003 R2 Datacenter Edition Windows Server 2003 with Service Pack 1 (SP1), Datacenter Edition 128 GB 16 GB with 4GT 1 TB Windows Server 2003 R2 Enterprise Edition Windows Server 2003 with Service Pack 1 (SP1), Enterprise Edition 64 GB 16 GB with 4GT 1 TB Windows Server 2003 R2 Standard Edition Windows Server 2003, Standard Edition SP1 Windows Server 2003, Standard Edition SP2 4 GB 32 GB Windows Server 2003, Datacenter Edition 128 GB 16 GB with 4GT 512 GB Windows Server 2003, Enterprise Edition 32 GB 16 GB with 4GT 64 GB Windows Server 2003, Standard Edition 4 GB 16 GB Windows Server 2003, Web Edition 2 GB Not applicable Windows Small Business Server 2003 4 GB Not applicable Windows Compute Cluster Server 2003 Not applicable 32 GB Version Limit in 32-bit Windows Limit in 64-bit Windows Windows XP 4 GB 128 GB Windows XP Starter Edition 512 MB Not applicable Version Limit in 32-bit Windows Windows 2000 Professional 4 GB Windows 2000 Server 4 GB Windows 2000 Advanced Server 8 GB Windows 2000 Datacenter Server 32 GB</description></item></channel></rss>