<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>s60v2 on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/s60v2/</link><description>Recent content in s60v2 on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 09:03:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/s60v2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A good, freeware text editor for your nokia symbian phone</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/15/a-good-freeware-text-editor-for-your-nokia-symbian-phone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 09:03:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/15/a-good-freeware-text-editor-for-your-nokia-symbian-phone/</guid><description>More and more phones have, these days, a decent text entry method - be it T9, qwerty keyboard or touch screen. Especially if you own a qwerty phone you might be interested in a good, native text editor application.
I searched, and DEdit came up. It has a ton of features, but more important you can easily edit text files on your phone. From it&amp;rsquo;s features one can note:
Remember last editing position in each text-file, that you edit; Remember user-defined positions in file Use many encodings, ascii and unicode Supports editing of big files (several megabytes or even more) Easy-to-use one-hand hotkeys Even more, it has versions for older phones too, like s60v2 not only s60v3.</description></item><item><title>New life into an old Nokia 7610</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/27/new-life-into-an-old-nokia-7610/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 10:04:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/27/new-life-into-an-old-nokia-7610/</guid><description>As promised I follow with an article on how to breathe new life into an aging phone.
Well, the 7610 was never lightning fast and over the years it became more and more troublesome, to the point where my wife thought it was about to break. She also got a good deal on a 500 Mb/month data plan so new software was in order. Although the prospect of a new gadget in the house was appealing I decided to see what was to be done with this one.</description></item></channel></rss>