<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>raid on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/raid/</link><description>Recent content in raid on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 06:02:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/raid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Verify SMART details for members of an Intel RST RAID volume</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/10/22/verify-smart-details-for-members-of-an-intel-rst-raid-volume/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 06:02:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/10/22/verify-smart-details-for-members-of-an-intel-rst-raid-volume/</guid><description>Sooo,
Be it because of the BIOS update to a beta or because of my drives but my RAID10 keeps failing. I documented before how to repair such a broken array but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go ahead with it too many times as data corruption is only one step away. Knowing that at least one of the disks has some minor issues (mdadm kicked it out some time ago when the disks were running under linux) I decided to check smart details and only keep only two of the disks in RAID1.</description></item><item><title>Intel RST RAID Non-RAID Disk after BIOS update</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/10/14/intel-rst-raid-non-raid-disk-after-bios-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 06:06:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/10/14/intel-rst-raid-non-raid-disk-after-bios-update/</guid><description>So, having nothing better to do and for no good reason I decided to update my workstation&amp;rsquo;s BIOS to the latest version released by Gigabyte. Since ignoring _the &amp;ldquo;__If it works don&amp;rsquo;t fix it&amp;rdquo; _mantra is always a good idea. Beautiful, after update two of my disks from a four disk RAID10 array were showing as Non-RAID Disk. I had backups but shuffling 2TB+ of data is never fun.
Initial reports were all grim, the Intel RST BIOS does not allow repairing.</description></item><item><title>Benchmark comparison of Intel RST RAID and Microsoft Storage Spaces pool</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/11/04/benchmark-comparison-of-intel-rst-raid-and-microsoft-storage-spaces-pool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 09:53:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/11/04/benchmark-comparison-of-intel-rst-raid-and-microsoft-storage-spaces-pool/</guid><description>I posted last time that I upgraded my workstation&amp;rsquo;s mechanical storage. Since I had a hard time deciding between using storage spaces and my motherboard&amp;rsquo;s Intel RST sollution I searched some comparisons but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any so I decided to make my own mini benchmark.
Hardware Intel I7 2600k Gigabyte GA-Z68XP-UD3P motherboard 4 WD 2TB Green drives (actually 3 x 2TB WD20EARS and 1 x 2TB WD20EADX) Benchmarks Storage spaces three drive parity Originally I was using just three of the disks (wanting to keep the fourth for offsite backups).</description></item><item><title>Trick Windows 8 into creating a RAID10 (striped mirrors) array</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/31/trick-windows-8-into-creating-a-raid10-striped-mirrors-array/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/31/trick-windows-8-into-creating-a-raid10-striped-mirrors-array/</guid><description>I recently had to upgrade the storage for my desktop and I thought that since I have a few left-over disks I&amp;rsquo;d try to build a RAID10 array - RAID10 is very cool because it gives performance close to striped arrays but enjoys the reliability of mirrored arrays. Wikipedia has a nice write-up if you want it.
I had two options - using the motherboard&amp;rsquo;s Intel controller or software RAID. Coming from the Linux world I was expecting software raid to be easy enough to configure - I was wrong apparently in the Windows world options are more limited (mirrors and stripes) with only recently in Windows 8 Storage Spaces offering more options.</description></item><item><title>Can you mirror a stripe? (a.k.a. 3 disks raid 10 or 1+0)</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/17/can-you-mirror-a-stripe-a-k-a-3-disks-raid-10-or-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 12:38:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/17/can-you-mirror-a-stripe-a-k-a-3-disks-raid-10-or-10/</guid><description>TL;DR Yes you can assemble a md device from a stripe and a disk.
Please don&amp;rsquo;t shoot! 🙂 I&amp;rsquo;m doing this on a testing server, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any idea about the long term stability and/or reliability and I don&amp;rsquo;t care this is a personal testing server. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do this (at least yet) on a production server.
The why, what and how below:
I am looking to assemble a &amp;ldquo;Frankenstein&amp;rdquo; virtualization server (i.</description></item><item><title>Load cycle count of Western Digital Green Drives and how to fix it from Linux</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/12/20/load-cycle-count-of-western-digital-green-drives-and-how-to-fix-it-from-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 12:17:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/12/20/load-cycle-count-of-western-digital-green-drives-and-how-to-fix-it-from-linux/</guid><description>I run a NAS at home. It used to have 3x2TB WD EARS drives. At some point I saw online some remarks about increased Load Cycle Count when using these drives in a NAS/RAID setup but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to check then. Modern Western Digital &amp;ldquo;Green&amp;rdquo; Drives include the Intellipark feature that stops the disk when not in use. Unfortunately, the default timer setting is not perfect on linux/unix systems, including many NAS, and leads to a dramatic increase of the Load Cycle Count value (SMART attribute #193).</description></item><item><title>FreeNAS</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/freenas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 10:32:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/freenas/</guid><description>Ok, so I wanted a NAS on my home network. Having just aquired a shabby XPC SK43G that simply refused to work as a htpc (it&amp;rsquo;s original purpose) I decided to set it up as a NAS (Network Attached Storage). I went out and bought a Western Digital Green 1 Tb Sata2 drive. The xpc refused to detect the drive until I set it via jumper as Sata1. I had to search on the Western Digital support pages, as the jumper settings are not documented on the drive itself.</description></item></channel></rss>