<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>root on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/root/</link><description>Recent content in root on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 09:11:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/root/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shrink (resize) a LVM volume</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/05/17/shrink-resize-a-lvm-volume/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 09:11:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/05/17/shrink-resize-a-lvm-volume/</guid><description>I found a lot of resources on resizing LVM volumes or volume groups. But resources on shrinking were a little scarce and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t easily find a simple step by step method listed, so here you go. Please note that the volume you intend to shrink must be unmounted. If you want to resize the root partition (because like me you didn&amp;rsquo;t noticed that the ubuntu server installer will alocate the full 500Gb HDD for the root) you will have to boot off a LiveCD.</description></item><item><title>Recover your lost linux slackware root password</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/recover-your-lost-linux-slackware-root-password/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 13:31:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/recover-your-lost-linux-slackware-root-password/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m an avid Slackware user. It was the distro I started using back in &amp;lsquo;98 and, even if I tried and used many others I still like it the most. Anyways these rules apply to many other flavours of linux.
One of the problems I faced is needing to make changes on inherited machines that nobody knew the passwords for. So, if you face the same problem, or you simply forgot the root password because you usually use a normal user account here&amp;rsquo;s what you have to do to reset the password.</description></item></channel></rss>