<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>slow on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/slow/</link><description>Recent content in slow on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 19:27:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/slow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up master-slave replication for mysql</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/30/setting-up-master-slave-replication-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 19:27:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/30/setting-up-master-slave-replication-for-mysql/</guid><description>So, I had to set-up master-slave replication. Here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it:
Why would one want to set-up this? Easy.
Spread the read load across multiple servers: you can use the MySQL master for writing (inserts, updates) and the slave(s) for reading (SELECT) This should speed up things nicely for your application.
Do the backups from the slave. You might have noticed that backing-up, especially big databases, slows things down. That happens because mysqldump locks tables as it reads them.</description></item><item><title>Enabling the MySQL slow query log</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/12/enabling-the-mysql-slow-query-log/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 16:32:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/12/enabling-the-mysql-slow-query-log/</guid><description>If you have a slow web app or website it might be because of unoptimized sql queries. You want to track and fix those and the mysql slow query log is very helpful here.
Enabling the slow query log MySQL prior to 5.1.0 requires adding a setting to the MySQL my.cnf file and restart the mysql daemon in order to log slow queries; from MySQL 5.1.0 onwards you can also change this dynamically without having to restart.</description></item><item><title>cbnet Ping Optimizer is killing a site</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/11/cbnet-ping-optimizer-is-killing-a-site/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 10:28:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/11/cbnet-ping-optimizer-is-killing-a-site/</guid><description>Some wise soul decided many moons ago that installing the aforementioned plugin on a site I host is a great ideea. The wise soul is long gone (admining websites for ngo&amp;rsquo;s as a volunteer is no fun for far too many come and goers:) ) Lately the site was getting more and more sluggish with no apparent reason. I decided to clean a bit the many modules he thought in his wisdom to install.</description></item></channel></rss>