<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>debian on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/debian/</link><description>Recent content in debian on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:41:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Full Disk Encryption on Hetzner Dedicated and Debian 10 Woes</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/06/18/full-disk-encryption-on-hetzner-dedicated-and-debian-10-woes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:41:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/06/18/full-disk-encryption-on-hetzner-dedicated-and-debian-10-woes/</guid><description>As absolutely nobody knows or uses I maintain an ansible role that can setup a Debian or Ubuntu machine with full disk encryption on Hetzner Robot (baremetal dedicated machines). But wait, you shout, Hetzner usually runs consumer grade stuff without kvm&amp;rsquo;s - how do you enter your password at bootime. Easy, the role sets up a minimal boot environment with a dropbear ssh server where you can login and do cryptroot-unlock.</description></item><item><title>Prevent update-grub from finding LVM based virtual machines</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/12/09/prevent-update-grub-from-finding-lvm-based-virtual-machines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 09:12:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/12/09/prevent-update-grub-from-finding-lvm-based-virtual-machines/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m running a debian based XEN box to host various virtual machines. Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been having an issue when running update-grub. All the partitions for the virtual machines are found and added to grub:
# update-grub2 [...] Found Debian GNU/Linux (7.7) on /dev/mapper/vg0-vm01-disk Found Debian GNU/Linux (7.7) on /dev/mapper/vg0-vm02-disk Found Slackware Linux (Slackware 14.1) on /dev/mapper/vg0-vm03-disk [...] It&amp;rsquo;s not a big issue as the xen kernel is still default but it&amp;rsquo;s annoying.</description></item><item><title>Email a list of updates from a Debian server.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/09/28/email-a-list-of-updates-from-a-debian-server/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 12:49:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/09/28/email-a-list-of-updates-from-a-debian-server/</guid><description>Do you run remote servers? Me too.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good ideea to keep them up to date. On the other hand I don&amp;rsquo;t like automatic updates, something might break when you least want or expect it. So I prefer to be notified of updates and choose myself the moment when to apply them. Following is a nice script that sends an email of available updates on a Debian system.</description></item><item><title>Unpacking a .deb file (including scripts)</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/23/unpacking-a-deb-file-including-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 10:11:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/23/unpacking-a-deb-file-including-scripts/</guid><description>While attempting to install a deb package on a slackware system I wanted to check the install script that the package runs. I tried the deb2tgz utility but unfortunately that only left me the files in the package in a ready to install .tgz file.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to unpack a .deb to obtain both scripts and files:
cd /tmp/somefolder tar x somepackage.deb This leaves you with two files:
control.tar.gz and data.</description></item><item><title>Installing Debian using only SSH</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/06/installing-debian-using-only-ssh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 11:40:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/06/installing-debian-using-only-ssh/</guid><description>I have a headless machine at home that I plan to use as a backup and development server. Even though I&amp;rsquo;m a Skackware guy I chose to install Debian on it. Of course I could have hooked a monitor and keyboard to it but for the sake of exercise I wanted to see if it&amp;rsquo;s possible to install debian using ssh from the very beginning.
The short answer: it&amp;rsquo;s possible &amp;hellip; maybe.</description></item></channel></rss>