<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>usb on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/usb/</link><description>Recent content in usb on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 06:51:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/usb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CentOS 6.x misses nobootwait fstab option.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/09/30/centos-6-x-misses-nobootwait-fstab-option/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 06:51:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/09/30/centos-6-x-misses-nobootwait-fstab-option/</guid><description>Recently I added a new storage disk to a cloud server. The issue is that this disk might not always be available at boot time. There is an easy fix for this kind of problems. The nobootwait mount option (like it would show in a fstab entry):
/dev/xvdd1 /storage ext4 defaults,nobootwait 0 0 Note that the fsck order of 0 already ensures that fsck will not hold the boot process by complaining the disk is missing.</description></item><item><title>Extending the range of a WiFi stick adapter</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/01/03/extending-the-range-of-a-wifi-stick-adapter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 12:03:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/01/03/extending-the-range-of-a-wifi-stick-adapter/</guid><description>I relocated some of my networking gear and by doing that one of my pc&amp;rsquo;s found itself in a blind spot of the wireless network. I decided to try and see if I can extend the range of the usb wireless adapter it uses. I had a few antennas available but unfortunately the usb adapter didn&amp;rsquo;t have a connector. I decided to solder the antenna wire directly:
First I pried open the usb adapter and located the internal antenna pads.</description></item><item><title>Disable charging of a Nokia N900 while USB connected.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/05/16/disable-charging-of-a-nokia-n900-while-usb-connected/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 20:45:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/05/16/disable-charging-of-a-nokia-n900-while-usb-connected/</guid><description>One of the joys of having a hackable computer serving as a phone is that you can do stuff which have no &amp;ldquo;option&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;settings&amp;rdquo;. Recently I wanted to see if I can connect it to an Android tablet (Samsung Galaxy Tab 10.1). I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Too bad as I could really use the extra 32Gb the n900 has to offer. It would connect but the tablet disconnects it as soon as the phone tries to start charging.</description></item><item><title>I have a linux Jukebox !</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/26/i-have-a-linux-jukebox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 19:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/26/i-have-a-linux-jukebox/</guid><description>Finally, after years of putting it away, after a few design changes and a fried motherboard I have a linux jukebox. Well, not a jukebox but more an internet radio.
Check at the bottom for the latest updates.
When I first had the ideea I noticed an old ~ &amp;rsquo;50s Blaupunkt Radio my father had in his basement. I investigated if the radio was worth restoring but the inside was rusted, the capacitors were long gone and most of the tubes were missing.</description></item><item><title>4×20 LCD screen with USB interface.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/31/4x20-lcd-screen-with-usb-interface/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2009 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/31/4x20-lcd-screen-with-usb-interface/</guid><description>Attaching an LCD screen to a pc is a pretty easy job. I am working on a jukebox that I wanted to a screen attached to. Although a HD44780 based LCD can be attached to the parallel port with almost no additional parts I wanted a more flexible solution, and I thought about microcontrollers with usb support. I found a thread here, where all the work is pretty much done. Thank you ch424.</description></item></channel></rss>