<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ssh on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/ssh/</link><description>Recent content in ssh on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:41:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/ssh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Full Disk Encryption on Hetzner Dedicated and Debian 10 Woes</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/06/18/full-disk-encryption-on-hetzner-dedicated-and-debian-10-woes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:41:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/06/18/full-disk-encryption-on-hetzner-dedicated-and-debian-10-woes/</guid><description>As absolutely nobody knows or uses I maintain an ansible role that can setup a Debian or Ubuntu machine with full disk encryption on Hetzner Robot (baremetal dedicated machines). But wait, you shout, Hetzner usually runs consumer grade stuff without kvm&amp;rsquo;s - how do you enter your password at bootime. Easy, the role sets up a minimal boot environment with a dropbear ssh server where you can login and do cryptroot-unlock.</description></item><item><title>SSH key based authentication fails on a new computer</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/06/02/ssh-key-based-authentication-fails-on-a-new-computer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 10:19:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/06/02/ssh-key-based-authentication-fails-on-a-new-computer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Having reinstalled one of my older laptops I noticed I cannot login using it&amp;rsquo;s private key. I was sure I backed up the original and properly restored it after reinstalling. I ran ssh -v to get more information:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Roaming not allowed by server&lt;/code> caught my eye. What the heck is that?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Regenerate SSH keys</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/06/14/regenerate-ssh-keys/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 12:04:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/06/14/regenerate-ssh-keys/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of virtualization. I find it very useful both on my workstation as for the servers. What this means is that I often clone virtual machines to repurpose, run tests or simply add web capacity for load balanced sites. One of the steps is that you have to regenerate the ssh keys (besides the usual suspects that are changing IP, hostname and so on) so you don&amp;rsquo;t have multiple hosts with the same ssh keys.</description></item><item><title>Speed-up X over ssh</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/01/31/speed-up-x-over-ssh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 08:07:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/01/31/speed-up-x-over-ssh/</guid><description>Even though I run a pretty fast network and vpn at home I still have the occasional hiccup running demanding applications (i.e. digikam) at home.
A few simple options can speed up X considerably. Connecting with the following parametters will enable a fast encryption cipher and also enables compression:
ssh -X -C -c blowfish-cbc,arcfour user@host.example.com Of course you can make this permanent by adding the following to /etc/ssh/ssh_config or even better only for the specific host in ~/.</description></item><item><title>Installing Debian using only SSH</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/06/installing-debian-using-only-ssh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 11:40:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/06/installing-debian-using-only-ssh/</guid><description>I have a headless machine at home that I plan to use as a backup and development server. Even though I&amp;rsquo;m a Skackware guy I chose to install Debian on it. Of course I could have hooked a monitor and keyboard to it but for the sake of exercise I wanted to see if it&amp;rsquo;s possible to install debian using ssh from the very beginning.
The short answer: it&amp;rsquo;s possible &amp;hellip; maybe.</description></item></channel></rss>