<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>compatibility on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/compatibility/</link><description>Recent content in compatibility on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 11:53:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/compatibility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[updated] List of Humble Bundle Games that work on the Sailfish OS Jolla Phone</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/01/03/list-of-humble-bundle-games-that-work-on-the-sailfish-os-jolla-phone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 11:53:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/01/03/list-of-humble-bundle-games-that-work-on-the-sailfish-os-jolla-phone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Being and old time Maemo fan I went and preordered the Jolla phone as soon as I could (March 2013 IIRC) and I&amp;rsquo;ve been happily playing with it ever since I got it. I like to play the occasional game on the go and so I bought many of the bundles that humblebundle offered. Happily they also offer an android application that functions like a store - you can see all the games you bought and download/install/update them. Follow &lt;a href="http://www.humblebundle.com/app">these directions to install the Humble Bundle&lt;/a> app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read bellow is a list of the games I own and as I get time to test them I will update the status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docx files in Office 2003</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/06/16/docx-files-in-office-2003/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 09:33:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/06/16/docx-files-in-office-2003/</guid><description>If you, like many of my clients regularly receive files from partners that have already upgraded to microsoft office 2007 have the annoyance that the files are always saved in the docx format (because people don&amp;rsquo;t go to the trouble to Save as office 2003) then you probably think that it&amp;rsquo;s time to upgrade. Right? Wrong! There is an easier sollution - not to mention a lot cheaper. Go to the microsoft website and download the</description></item><item><title>Running 16 bit apps in Windows 7 64 bit</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/04/03/running-16-bit-apps-in-windows-7-64-bit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 10:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/04/03/running-16-bit-apps-in-windows-7-64-bit/</guid><description>We got for my wife a much needed upgrade for her aging Toshiba laptop. The new one came with Windows 7 64 bit. I managed to get all her old software working with the exception of Oxford Superlex. This one is a dictionary from the Windows 3.11 ages. It worked fine in all windowses we had (98, 2000, XP) but having a 64 bit Windows killed it because the support for 16 bits apps is dropped in 64 bits versions of Vista and 7.</description></item></channel></rss>