<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>share on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/share/</link><description>Recent content in share on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 09:09:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/share/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache 2.2 will not serve corectly from CIFS mounted share</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/27/apache-2-2-will-not-serve-corectly-from-cifs-mounted-share/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 09:09:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/27/apache-2-2-will-not-serve-corectly-from-cifs-mounted-share/</guid><description>I have a home server I use for all kinds of stuff when I&amp;rsquo;m away. I have set it up recently so that it can serve a folder mounted over the network from a Windows machine.
And this is where the fun started!
The folders and files appear correctly, I can navigate and I can download them. Only that the files, even if apparently having the same size are corrupted. I checked the FollowSymLinks and as expected was set as required.</description></item><item><title>How to mount a windows share (samba) from the linux command line</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/24/how-to-mount-a-windows-share-samba-from-the-linux-command-line/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 18:03:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/24/how-to-mount-a-windows-share-samba-from-the-linux-command-line/</guid><description>As you know Linux does not use drive letters like Windows does. All files are organized under a big tree hierarchy. We use the mount command to mount partitions and this is the same command used to mount remote windows partition or windows shares.
Please note that you&amp;rsquo;ll need to know the following:
Windows username and password (the ones needed to access the share) The machine and share name. Something like //xpdesktop/pictures Have root access on the linux machine Login on your linux machine as root.</description></item></channel></rss>