<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>freeware on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/freeware/</link><description>Recent content in freeware on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 12:36:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/freeware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My recomandations for Symbian 5th edition</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/10/13/my-recomandations-for-symbian-5th-edition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 12:36:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/10/13/my-recomandations-for-symbian-5th-edition/</guid><description>Before you ask, no, I didn&amp;rsquo;t gave up my trusted E71. But my wife&amp;rsquo;s had it with her old 7610 so we upgraded her phone. After some deliberation, and her not liking the design of the e55 and e52 she finally settled for a Nokia 5800.
As you know that&amp;rsquo;s a 5th edition, touchscreen phone. I was a bit reticent because it&amp;rsquo;s never a good idea to get the first product from a series (that being the first Nokia touchscreen), still after reading a few reviews getting the 5800 seemed like a good idea.</description></item><item><title>Small but useful Windows junk cleaner</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/19/small-but-useful/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 08:59:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/19/small-but-useful/</guid><description>I just stumbled upon a nice little utility. It&amp;rsquo;s called ATF Cleaner. What it does? What you always do when you clean up a computer or remove a virus: it cleans temporary folders, temporary internet files and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s what you basically do manually every time you start working on a computer with problems.
It&amp;rsquo;s small, fast and useful but as it&amp;rsquo;s always the case with utilities that erase files you should be careful.</description></item><item><title>I’m not using Gravity for Twitter access on my phone</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/14/im-not-using-gravity-for-twitter-access-on-my-phone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 13:06:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/14/im-not-using-gravity-for-twitter-access-on-my-phone/</guid><description>Even though I like Gravity a lot, I chose a simpler FREEWARE symbian native application as a client for Twitter - Tweets60:
It&amp;rsquo;s simple, fast, and has access point prioritization built in.
It may not be as feature full as Gravity, but it&amp;rsquo;s free - so you can&amp;rsquo;t argue there. You can write your tweets, follow others and click links and more. Even more I find it faster than Gravity. Of course if you need or want to be able to upload pictures and other advanced features that Tweet60 misses for now you&amp;rsquo;ll need to shell out the (modest) price of Gravity.</description></item><item><title>A free book about PIC Microcontrollers</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/a-free-book-about-pic-microcontrollers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 11:22:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/a-free-book-about-pic-microcontrollers/</guid><description>As you might have noticed from my posts I am always in for a free lunch.
So, this would be free lunch for your brain. Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t use or plan to use Mikroelektronika products you might want to know that they have a free book about PIC microcontrolers on their website: here.
It&amp;rsquo;s not tied up to any of their development systems but it does focus on the PIC16F887, and even if the English used is not the best possible it still gets the job done.</description></item><item><title>How to watermark you pictures for free</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/22/how-to-watermark-you-pictures-for-free/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2009 10:54:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/22/how-to-watermark-you-pictures-for-free/</guid><description>Ever since I post pictures on the internet I searched for a way to watermark them. I am not paranoiac but I want others to respect my work. I used to use Fast Stone Image Viewer. It&amp;rsquo;s fast, free for personal use and has an array of functions that can be applied in Batch Mode, many useful if you publish your pictures online.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick step by step:
Start Fast Stone, select the images you want to watermark and press F3.</description></item><item><title>A good, freeware text editor for your nokia symbian phone</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/15/a-good-freeware-text-editor-for-your-nokia-symbian-phone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 09:03:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/15/a-good-freeware-text-editor-for-your-nokia-symbian-phone/</guid><description>More and more phones have, these days, a decent text entry method - be it T9, qwerty keyboard or touch screen. Especially if you own a qwerty phone you might be interested in a good, native text editor application.
I searched, and DEdit came up. It has a ton of features, but more important you can easily edit text files on your phone. From it&amp;rsquo;s features one can note:
Remember last editing position in each text-file, that you edit; Remember user-defined positions in file Use many encodings, ascii and unicode Supports editing of big files (several megabytes or even more) Easy-to-use one-hand hotkeys Even more, it has versions for older phones too, like s60v2 not only s60v3.</description></item><item><title>Smart connect update</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/10/smart-connect-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 15:53:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/10/smart-connect-update/</guid><description>Remeber my article in which I was praising Smart Connect for filling the inexplicable gap in the access point configuration on newer E series nokia phones?
Well I have a small update. It&amp;rsquo;s crap. From time to time my phone was unnable to connect to the internet, be it 3g or wi-fi untill I restarted it. I kept thinking it&amp;rsquo;s the phones problem, and waited for a firmware update. Well I managed to track the problem: it&amp;rsquo;s Smart Connect.</description></item><item><title>The quest for mobile Youtube is over</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/10/the-quest-for-mobile-youtube-is-over/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 15:44:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/10/the-quest-for-mobile-youtube-is-over/</guid><description>Ever since Flash 3.0 came out and I managed to install it on my Nokia E61 phone I have been using one or other mobile youtube application. It&amp;rsquo;s a handy app to have when you want to kill some time. I started with emTube which was pretty good, but never got updated and for me it stopped working.
Mobitubia saved the day, especially with it&amp;rsquo;s nice interface, ability to save files for later viewing and so on.</description></item><item><title>What I add to a fresh install of Windows XP</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/01/what-i-add-to-a-fresh-install-of-windows-xp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 08:30:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/01/what-i-add-to-a-fresh-install-of-windows-xp/</guid><description>Yes, yes, I know, Windows 7 is all the rage today. But, XP is still widely used and for now is the operating system I need to install on 90% of the cases. Of course first I install Windows XP, then the pc&amp;rsquo;s drivers and utilities, then I add whatever commercial software the client uses. After that, from case to case I always add some of the following:
Security If it&amp;rsquo;s a home user that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a paid antivirus solution I install AVG free or Avast Home edition.</description></item><item><title>Take your mobile phone for a "Swim"</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/take-your-mobile-phone-for-a-swim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 08:08:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/take-your-mobile-phone-for-a-swim/</guid><description>At one point I&amp;rsquo;ve been the shamed user of a Sony Ericsson v610i. Pretty simple candybar phone. Although it had one function that put my next phone (the Nokia E61) and my current phone to shame. It had syncml capabilities with the option of automatic, periodic syncing. Guess what&amp;hellip; the flagship E series device of its time didn&amp;rsquo;t!
Open source to the rescue. I searched for a sollution for some time, eventually giving up, until I discovered, recently the Bergamot Project with its Swim project.</description></item><item><title>What’s installed on my Nokia E71 and why.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/whats-installed-on-my-nokia-e71-and-why/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 09:37:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/whats-installed-on-my-nokia-e71-and-why/</guid><description>As you might have noticed I am very fond of open source or freeware software. I like the community and the development pace of such projects, and of course I am fond of the price. So, before watching another top 10 freeware list, here&amp;rsquo;s a list from someone who actually used the programs for months or years and uses them on a daily basis:
1. Home screen From left to right:</description></item><item><title>Combofix</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/25/combofix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 13:09:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/25/combofix/</guid><description>When I first discovered malware that was not a virus I simply used regedit to remove it&amp;rsquo;s entries and prevent it from starting at boot, then I simply erased them. After a while, as spyware became more and more sophisticated I discovered Lavasoft&amp;rsquo;s Ad-Aware. Than Spybot Search and Destroy.
Lately it seems to me that Ad-aware is lagging more and more behind Spybot. A friend of mine recomended Combofix so I gave it a shot.</description></item></channel></rss>