<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>firefox on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/firefox/</link><description>Recent content in firefox on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 11:51:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/firefox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Optimize Firefox’s sqlite databases</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/08/07/optimize-firefoxs-sqlite-databases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 11:51:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/08/07/optimize-firefoxs-sqlite-databases/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a handy one-liner to tune a bit your Firefox:
for file in ~/.mozilla/firefox/*/*.sqlite; do sqlite3 $file &amp;#39;VACUUM;&amp;#39;;done What this does ie optimize every sqlite database in your account&amp;rsquo;s profiles. You can even add this line to a script to start on boot or by cron. Worth noting that Firefox should probably not run while you do this.</description></item><item><title>Open a magnet link on a remote (or local) transmission server.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/07/17/open-a-magnet-link-on-a-remote-or-local-transmission-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 19:37:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/07/17/open-a-magnet-link-on-a-remote-or-local-transmission-server/</guid><description>One of the services I run on my home server is a transmission daemon. I use it mainly to download images for my Raspberry PI, new distro iso&amp;rsquo;s to play with in Virtualbox and so on. Recently there&amp;rsquo;s been a move to replace torrent links with magnet links. I found a nice way to open those directly on the remote instance of the transmission daemon.
First create a script, let&amp;rsquo;s call it simply magnet.</description></item><item><title>Firefox 4 on linux change to one button menu and make it nice and orange</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/04/27/firefox-4-on-linux-change-to-one-button-menu-and-make-it-nice-and-orange/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 05:13:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/04/27/firefox-4-on-linux-change-to-one-button-menu-and-make-it-nice-and-orange/</guid><description>When I upgraded to Firefox 4 on my linux machines I was disappointed to see that the classic menu bar remained. I&amp;rsquo;m not necesarily a fan of the new ribbon interfaces but since I don&amp;rsquo;t use the menu often and so prefer to use the space for something useful, like the tabs.
Reducing the menu bar to a button is easy.
Right click on the menu bar and uncheck Menu bar</description></item><item><title>Get the new Firefox 4.0 beta for Linux 64 bit.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/26/get-the-new-firefox-4-0-beta-for-linux-64-bit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 13:36:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/26/get-the-new-firefox-4-0-beta-for-linux-64-bit/</guid><description>I wanted to play a bit with the Mozilla Firefox 4.0 beta. Well, if you go to the download site there&amp;rsquo;s no apparent way to download the 64 bit version of Firefox. This is where I got it:
ftp://ftp.mozilla.org/pub/firefox/releases/4.0b1</description></item><item><title>Configure the behaviour of backspace in Firefox for Linux</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/03/15/configure-the-behaviour-of-backspace-in-firefox-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 21:18:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/03/15/configure-the-behaviour-of-backspace-in-firefox-for-linux/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a mystery for me why on windows firefox developers have conceived one use for backspace and another for firefox on linux.
If you are coming from windows and moving onto linux you might be used to press backspace to go back one page in Firefox. Well you&amp;rsquo;re in for a small surprise - id doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.
You need to go to about:config browser.backspace_action as either 0 or 1.</description></item><item><title>Gears available for Firefox 3.5 – sord of</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/07/gears-available-for-firefox-3-5-sord-of/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 09:03:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/07/gears-available-for-firefox-3-5-sord-of/</guid><description>Like I mentioned in my previous post Firefox 3.5 is still not supported by google gears. I don&amp;rsquo;t need it for Gmail but I use the turbo feature of WordPress.
Well, a good soul over at the Google Gears User Group made a custom build. You should treat it as beta quality. It works for me on Windows but YMMV.
Probably official support is right around the corner if the fix is already in the latest source.</description></item><item><title>Firefox 3.5 fails to impress me. Google Gears also missing.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/firefox-3-5-fails-to-impress-me-google-gears-is-also-missing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 11:43:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/firefox-3-5-fails-to-impress-me-google-gears-is-also-missing/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Firefox 3.5 for some time now - alpha, beta, rc and now final.
In my opinion firefox fails to improve performance as promised. It has some new features, it has some bad new features and it misses the speed we want and need. Ajax sites seem just as slow as they were in Firefox 3.0. It still isn&amp;rsquo;t 100 on the ACID 3 test and so on.</description></item></channel></rss>