<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>jolla on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/jolla/</link><description>Recent content in jolla on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 11:53:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/jolla/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[updated] List of Humble Bundle Games that work on the Sailfish OS Jolla Phone</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/01/03/list-of-humble-bundle-games-that-work-on-the-sailfish-os-jolla-phone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 11:53:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/01/03/list-of-humble-bundle-games-that-work-on-the-sailfish-os-jolla-phone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Being and old time Maemo fan I went and preordered the Jolla phone as soon as I could (March 2013 IIRC) and I&amp;rsquo;ve been happily playing with it ever since I got it. I like to play the occasional game on the go and so I bought many of the bundles that humblebundle offered. Happily they also offer an android application that functions like a store - you can see all the games you bought and download/install/update them. Follow &lt;a href="http://www.humblebundle.com/app">these directions to install the Humble Bundle&lt;/a> app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read bellow is a list of the games I own and as I get time to test them I will update the status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A simple retweet bot using a collocated Raspberry PI</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/09/13/a-simple-retweet-bot-using-a-collocated-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 08:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/09/13/a-simple-retweet-bot-using-a-collocated-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>I have a Raspberry PI freely collocated by the nice people at pcextreme. Being a Jolla fan I found a new use for it. I made a Retweet bot that retweets everything #Jolla.
It&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple. First you need to define your new twitter app here. Install on your raspberry the tweepy twitter python library. Warning usually it would be as easy as pip install tweepy but the current version has a bug which means you have to install a patched version of tweepy found here: git clone https://github.</description></item></channel></rss>