<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:41:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Full Disk Encryption on Hetzner Dedicated and Debian 10 Woes</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/06/18/full-disk-encryption-on-hetzner-dedicated-and-debian-10-woes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:41:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/06/18/full-disk-encryption-on-hetzner-dedicated-and-debian-10-woes/</guid><description>As absolutely nobody knows or uses I maintain an ansible role that can setup a Debian or Ubuntu machine with full disk encryption on Hetzner Robot (baremetal dedicated machines). But wait, you shout, Hetzner usually runs consumer grade stuff without kvm&amp;rsquo;s - how do you enter your password at bootime. Easy, the role sets up a minimal boot environment with a dropbear ssh server where you can login and do cryptroot-unlock.</description></item><item><title>Can you mirror a stripe? (a.k.a. 3 disks raid 10 or 1+0)</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/17/can-you-mirror-a-stripe-a-k-a-3-disks-raid-10-or-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 12:38:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/17/can-you-mirror-a-stripe-a-k-a-3-disks-raid-10-or-10/</guid><description>TL;DR Yes you can assemble a md device from a stripe and a disk.
Please don&amp;rsquo;t shoot! 🙂 I&amp;rsquo;m doing this on a testing server, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any idea about the long term stability and/or reliability and I don&amp;rsquo;t care this is a personal testing server. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do this (at least yet) on a production server.
The why, what and how below:
I am looking to assemble a &amp;ldquo;Frankenstein&amp;rdquo; virtualization server (i.</description></item><item><title>Linux on the Acer E3-111 – Aspire E3-111-C5FN</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/09/05/linux-on-the-acer-e3-111-aspire-e3-111-c5fn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 08:39:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/09/05/linux-on-the-acer-e3-111-aspire-e3-111-c5fn/</guid><description>I gave up on using a tablet and sold mine some time ago. My old toshiba m100 laptop was to heavy and too old to lug around when on holiday (mainly to download photos) so I decided to buy a small laptop to replace it. 10&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; is too small for me and so I decided on an 11&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; low cost system.
I bought an Acer Aspire E3-111 instead of competing models from Asus and others because I found a good deal on it and because of the quad core CPU - Intel® Celeron® N2930 - that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find on any other machine.</description></item><item><title>Stream music from home when you are away</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/12/13/stream-music-from-home-when-you-are-away/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 07:03:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/12/13/stream-music-from-home-when-you-are-away/</guid><description>I run a pretty powerful microitx system as my home router. Since it&amp;rsquo;s always on (as oposed to my nas) I decided to add some storage so I can host my music and some tv shows. I checked some projects and stopped to test Sockso.The site is simple and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really scream &amp;ldquo;open source project&amp;rdquo; but sockso seems really good at what it does. It works both as a gui and as a server tool and is available for windows, linux and mac.</description></item><item><title>Load cycle count of Western Digital Green Drives and how to fix it from Linux</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/12/20/load-cycle-count-of-western-digital-green-drives-and-how-to-fix-it-from-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 12:17:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/12/20/load-cycle-count-of-western-digital-green-drives-and-how-to-fix-it-from-linux/</guid><description>I run a NAS at home. It used to have 3x2TB WD EARS drives. At some point I saw online some remarks about increased Load Cycle Count when using these drives in a NAS/RAID setup but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to check then. Modern Western Digital &amp;ldquo;Green&amp;rdquo; Drives include the Intellipark feature that stops the disk when not in use. Unfortunately, the default timer setting is not perfect on linux/unix systems, including many NAS, and leads to a dramatic increase of the Load Cycle Count value (SMART attribute #193).</description></item><item><title>Remove duplicates from the current folder</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/09/04/remove-duplicates-from-the-current-folder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 12:01:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/09/04/remove-duplicates-from-the-current-folder/</guid><description>I needed today to remove duplicate files from a big folder (8Gb+, 10000+ files). I use the nice fdupes program written by Adrian Lopez
fdupes -rdN . Note the point after the parameters. That means to search inside the current folder. A path could be provided instead of it. The options are:
-r means search recursively -d means delete. use carefully and read the man page to understand what could go wrong!</description></item><item><title>Microsoft updates Skype for Linux</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/06/15/microsoft-updates-skype-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 06:08:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/06/15/microsoft-updates-skype-for-linux/</guid><description>Or in other news, hell froze over 🙂 Some people complained about the new interface, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to be agains the flow here and say that I actually quite like it.
It&amp;rsquo;s not like skype for linux was ever active but since Microsoft aquired them I pretty much wrote off any updates. It seems I, like many others was wrong. Probably it has something to do with the new advertising features introduced lately&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Removed ntfs partition reappears</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/13/removed-ntfs-partition-reappears/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 08:16:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/13/removed-ntfs-partition-reappears/</guid><description>So, I was repartitioning a harddrive that used to be a windows disk. I removed the ntfs partition that was spanning the whole drive and created a linux layout instead (two linux partitions and one swap). After writing the partition table the first partition on the disk failed to format. Returning to fdisk I saw that the first partition was still of type NTFS. So I changed the type once more and wrote the partition table to disk.</description></item><item><title>request_module: runaway loop modprobe binfmt-464c</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/07/request_module-runaway-loop-modprobe-binfmt-464c/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 13:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/07/request_module-runaway-loop-modprobe-binfmt-464c/</guid><description>I added a new disk to my HP N40L and moved the boot disk to another SATA port, which meant reconfiguring lilo. Strange enough after setting everything up I got:
request_module: runaway loop modprobe binfmt-464c right after the kernel loading.
Long story short this message means you are trying to boot a 32bit system with a 64 bit kernel (maybe the other way around will spit something similar). I set the boot parameter wrong and I was actually trying to boot and old 32 bit linux install that was still around on one of the drives in the NAS</description></item><item><title>Make sensors report temperature on slackware64-current with an Intel I7 2600k</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/27/make-sensors-report-temperature-on-slackware64-current-with-an-intel-i7-2600k/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 20:01:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/27/make-sensors-report-temperature-on-slackware64-current-with-an-intel-i7-2600k/</guid><description>For some reasons the required modules don&amp;rsquo;t get loaded. Add the following to /etc/rc.d/rc.modules right above the line reading ### Mouse support:
### by SV for i2600k temperature /sbin/modprobe coretemp /sbin/modprobe pkgtemp Now sensors report the temperatures.</description></item><item><title>Quickly check if a process is running or not</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/12/22/quickly-check-if-a-process-is-running-or-not/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 08:29:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/12/22/quickly-check-if-a-process-is-running-or-not/</guid><description>When writting bash scripts one often needs to see if a process is running or not I like the following code; though I&amp;rsquo;m sure many ways of doing this exists, what&amp;rsquo;s your favorite?
if [ -z &amp;#34;$(pgrep process)&amp;#34; ]; then echo &amp;#34;process is not running&amp;#34; else echo &amp;#34;process is running&amp;#34; fi</description></item><item><title>Working mediatomb config.xml for Samsung UE37C5000</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/09/13/working-mediatomb-config-xml-for-samsung-ue37c5000/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 14:11:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/09/13/working-mediatomb-config-xml-for-samsung-ue37c5000/</guid><description>I have a NAS and an Samsung UE37C5000 UPNP/DLNA enabled led TV. Streaming from the first to the second should be easy, right? Well after a few tweaks MediaTomb makes it possible.
I don&amp;rsquo;t say this is the best configuration possible but it&amp;rsquo;s the one that works INCLUDING pause and fast forwarding.
Relevant from the default are the custom header, extended protocol info and the mkv and avi lines.
MediaTomb uuid:0f53d0ff-5951-4d27-8fa7-06ce378ae789 /var/lib/mediatomb /usr/share/mediatomb/web mediatomb.</description></item><item><title>Make Joomla 1.0 work with PHP 5.3</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/23/make-joomla-1-0-work-with-php-5-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 10:43:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/23/make-joomla-1-0-work-with-php-5-3/</guid><description>With the recent posts regarding resurrecting old stuff, recently I had to resurrect a Joomla 1.0 site. Soon enough I discovered that the home page doesn&amp;rsquo;t display correctly. No errors, just lots of white space :). The problem is that Joomla 1.0 is not really made for PHP 5.3. Of course I could have started a virtual machine with the right environment but I wanted it running along some newer sites.</description></item><item><title>Shrink (resize) a LVM volume</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/05/17/shrink-resize-a-lvm-volume/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 09:11:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/05/17/shrink-resize-a-lvm-volume/</guid><description>I found a lot of resources on resizing LVM volumes or volume groups. But resources on shrinking were a little scarce and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t easily find a simple step by step method listed, so here you go. Please note that the volume you intend to shrink must be unmounted. If you want to resize the root partition (because like me you didn&amp;rsquo;t noticed that the ubuntu server installer will alocate the full 500Gb HDD for the root) you will have to boot off a LiveCD.</description></item><item><title>How to mount a windows share (samba) from the linux command line</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/24/how-to-mount-a-windows-share-samba-from-the-linux-command-line/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 18:03:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/24/how-to-mount-a-windows-share-samba-from-the-linux-command-line/</guid><description>As you know Linux does not use drive letters like Windows does. All files are organized under a big tree hierarchy. We use the mount command to mount partitions and this is the same command used to mount remote windows partition or windows shares.
Please note that you&amp;rsquo;ll need to know the following:
Windows username and password (the ones needed to access the share) The machine and share name. Something like //xpdesktop/pictures Have root access on the linux machine Login on your linux machine as root.</description></item><item><title>Slackware 13 is here</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/09/01/slackware-13-is-here/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 07:48:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/09/01/slackware-13-is-here/</guid><description>Yupeee, a new toy. Slacware 13.0 is out, with an official and in sync 64bit version too. Finally upgraded to KDE 4.2.x.
Get yours while it&amp;rsquo;s hot. And don&amp;rsquo;t forget to support the project by buying the dvd&amp;rsquo;s from the Slackware store.
Have fun!</description></item><item><title>I have a linux Jukebox !</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/26/i-have-a-linux-jukebox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 19:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/26/i-have-a-linux-jukebox/</guid><description>Finally, after years of putting it away, after a few design changes and a fried motherboard I have a linux jukebox. Well, not a jukebox but more an internet radio.
Check at the bottom for the latest updates.
When I first had the ideea I noticed an old ~ &amp;rsquo;50s Blaupunkt Radio my father had in his basement. I investigated if the radio was worth restoring but the inside was rusted, the capacitors were long gone and most of the tubes were missing.</description></item><item><title>Recover your lost linux slackware root password</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/recover-your-lost-linux-slackware-root-password/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 13:31:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/recover-your-lost-linux-slackware-root-password/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m an avid Slackware user. It was the distro I started using back in &amp;lsquo;98 and, even if I tried and used many others I still like it the most. Anyways these rules apply to many other flavours of linux.
One of the problems I faced is needing to make changes on inherited machines that nobody knew the passwords for. So, if you face the same problem, or you simply forgot the root password because you usually use a normal user account here&amp;rsquo;s what you have to do to reset the password.</description></item></channel></rss>