<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>16f887 on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/16f887/</link><description>Recent content in 16f887 on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 16:30:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/16f887/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open source ADC read function</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/14/open-source-adc-read-function/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 16:30:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/14/open-source-adc-read-function/</guid><description>Yes, I know, mikroC has it&amp;rsquo;s own ADC library, but as always I am a sucker for open source. So I decided to write my own adc read function, so I can better understand the PIC ADC converter operation. And, in the good spirit of open source I decided to share my code. The following code is the ADC on LCD example supplied by MikroElectronika with their EasyPic5 board, and it&amp;rsquo;s written in MikroC Pro.</description></item><item><title>A free book about PIC Microcontrollers</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/a-free-book-about-pic-microcontrollers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 11:22:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/a-free-book-about-pic-microcontrollers/</guid><description>As you might have noticed from my posts I am always in for a free lunch.
So, this would be free lunch for your brain. Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t use or plan to use Mikroelektronika products you might want to know that they have a free book about PIC microcontrolers on their website: here.
It&amp;rsquo;s not tied up to any of their development systems but it does focus on the PIC16F887, and even if the English used is not the best possible it still gets the job done.</description></item><item><title>Temperature graph on GLCD with EasyPic5</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/18/temperature-graph-on-glcd-with-easypic5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 17:17:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/18/temperature-graph-on-glcd-with-easypic5/</guid><description>This is a small project I did for school. I am using the easypic 5 board from mikroelectronica to display a linegraph of the temperature read every second by the DS1820 sensor and displays it on the KS0108 based GLCD. I am using the OneWire and GLCD libraries that come with the mikroC compiler.
I am using a PIC16F887 mounted on the board. You might need to adjust the code if you use a different microcontroler / development board.</description></item></channel></rss>