<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mikroc on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/mikroc/</link><description>Recent content in mikroc on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 15:23:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/mikroc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KS0108 Graphics Library for PIC16F microcontrollers</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/01/ks0108-graphics-library-for-pic16f-microcontrollers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 15:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/01/ks0108-graphics-library-for-pic16f-microcontrollers/</guid><description>Not that I&amp;rsquo;m not happy with the default mikroC library for the KS0108 graphic displays, as I always I wanted something with the source available. Considering that I&amp;rsquo;m a beginner with microcontrolers having the source available to hack around is a very valuable learning tool.
The project is based on the source found here:
http://en.radzio.dxp.pl/ks0108/
The source is made pretty universal, still it took some work and modifications to have it working in mikroC.</description></item><item><title>Open source ADC read function</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/14/open-source-adc-read-function/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 16:30:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/14/open-source-adc-read-function/</guid><description>Yes, I know, mikroC has it&amp;rsquo;s own ADC library, but as always I am a sucker for open source. So I decided to write my own adc read function, so I can better understand the PIC ADC converter operation. And, in the good spirit of open source I decided to share my code. The following code is the ADC on LCD example supplied by MikroElectronika with their EasyPic5 board, and it&amp;rsquo;s written in MikroC Pro.</description></item><item><title>Temperature graph on GLCD with EasyPic5</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/18/temperature-graph-on-glcd-with-easypic5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 17:17:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/18/temperature-graph-on-glcd-with-easypic5/</guid><description>This is a small project I did for school. I am using the easypic 5 board from mikroelectronica to display a linegraph of the temperature read every second by the DS1820 sensor and displays it on the KS0108 based GLCD. I am using the OneWire and GLCD libraries that come with the mikroC compiler.
I am using a PIC16F887 mounted on the board. You might need to adjust the code if you use a different microcontroler / development board.</description></item></channel></rss>