<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>google on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/google/</link><description>Recent content in google on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 10:17:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating Gerrit to Google OAuth from Google OpenID</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/09/migrating-gerrit-to-google-oauth-from-google-openid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 10:17:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/09/migrating-gerrit-to-google-oauth-from-google-openid/</guid><description>I expect this post to be obsolete pretty soon, but for now I expect this will help you skip many of the issues and questions I had going forward with upgrading Gerrit and switching to Google OAuth from OpenID.
This post is not exhaustive, I trust that you are familiar with Gerrit if you&amp;rsquo;ve come so far. I am running a gerrit installation that was stuck at v2.10 as all our users used Google OpenID.</description></item><item><title>Running gcp.py from cron</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/03/running-gcp-py-from-cron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 10:16:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/03/running-gcp-py-from-cron/</guid><description>On my backup server I run gcp.py from gdatacopier to backup my google docs. I had to fix two issues in order to get it to run from a bash script:
the PYTHONPATH had to be exported prior to running, or the script will fail because it requires gdata-python-client the LANG envronment has to be set otherwise it will spill the following error in the log (if you bother to log the output from cron that is, otherwise it will just not work and you won&amp;rsquo;t know why, because the script works fine when ran manually) Traceback (most recent call last): File &amp;#34;/usr/local/bin/gcp.</description></item><item><title>List of open dns servers</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/list-of-open-dns-servers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 20:24:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/list-of-open-dns-servers/</guid><description>This is a growing list of Open DNS servers available around the world.
I also maintain a list of ip address of various isp providers.
Google Pubic DNS 8.8.8.8 8.8.4.4 OpenDNS **** 208.67.220.220 208.67.222.222. Open DNS also makes available a third and fourth dns server with identical service to the first two:
208.67.220.222 208.67.222.220 ScrubIT 67.138.54.100 207.225.209.66 Level 3 Communications 4.2.2.1 4.2.2.2 4.2.2.3 4.2.2.4 4.2.2.5 4.2.2.6 OpenNIC 58.6.115.42 (Queensland, Australia) 202.</description></item><item><title>Installed Google Custom Search, no results are showing.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/30/google-custom-search-no-results/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 18:41:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/30/google-custom-search-no-results/</guid><description>I did a website for a friend, a kind of a knowledge base and installed google custom search on it. To my surprise google stubornly kept showing no search results. I redid the custom search settings, paying close attention to the domains on which I wanted the search limited on, but still no results.
I took a quick walk on the Google Help boulevard but I didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything. A google search later and I found numerous causes: wrong definitions for the domains on which the search is limited, wrong integration of the code, wrong definition of the result page the form should point to.</description></item><item><title>Chrome OS</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/22/chrome-os/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 22:40:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/22/chrome-os/</guid><description>Since everybody is talking about it I really wanted to experience the all new big thing Google is preparing for us. The fine people over at Techcrunch already prepared a nice tutorial on how to install and run a Chrome virtual machine image so I wont go on to reinvent the wheel.
Let me just say that I am completely unimpressed. It&amp;rsquo;s a linux kernel with a browser on top of it.</description></item><item><title>Gears available for Firefox 3.5 – sord of</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/07/gears-available-for-firefox-3-5-sord-of/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 09:03:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/07/gears-available-for-firefox-3-5-sord-of/</guid><description>Like I mentioned in my previous post Firefox 3.5 is still not supported by google gears. I don&amp;rsquo;t need it for Gmail but I use the turbo feature of WordPress.
Well, a good soul over at the Google Gears User Group made a custom build. You should treat it as beta quality. It works for me on Windows but YMMV.
Probably official support is right around the corner if the fix is already in the latest source.</description></item><item><title>Firefox 3.5 fails to impress me. Google Gears also missing.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/firefox-3-5-fails-to-impress-me-google-gears-is-also-missing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 11:43:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/firefox-3-5-fails-to-impress-me-google-gears-is-also-missing/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Firefox 3.5 for some time now - alpha, beta, rc and now final.
In my opinion firefox fails to improve performance as promised. It has some new features, it has some bad new features and it misses the speed we want and need. Ajax sites seem just as slow as they were in Firefox 3.0. It still isn&amp;rsquo;t 100 on the ACID 3 test and so on.</description></item></channel></rss>