<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 11:24:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use Vagrant on Windows with Ansible under Cygwin</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/02/04/use-vagrant-on-windows-with-ansible-under-cygwin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 11:24:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/02/04/use-vagrant-on-windows-with-ansible-under-cygwin/</guid><description>If due to some reason you have to run vagrant under windows and plan on using Ansible you will need a couple of wrappers.
ansible-playbook.bat has to be in the Windows PATH;
ansible-winpath-playbook.sh is called by ansible-playbook.bat to change paths from Windows style paths to *nix style paths that ansible under cygwin can understand.</description></item><item><title>Trick Windows 8 into creating a RAID10 (striped mirrors) array</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/31/trick-windows-8-into-creating-a-raid10-striped-mirrors-array/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/31/trick-windows-8-into-creating-a-raid10-striped-mirrors-array/</guid><description>I recently had to upgrade the storage for my desktop and I thought that since I have a few left-over disks I&amp;rsquo;d try to build a RAID10 array - RAID10 is very cool because it gives performance close to striped arrays but enjoys the reliability of mirrored arrays. Wikipedia has a nice write-up if you want it.
I had two options - using the motherboard&amp;rsquo;s Intel controller or software RAID. Coming from the Linux world I was expecting software raid to be easy enough to configure - I was wrong apparently in the Windows world options are more limited (mirrors and stripes) with only recently in Windows 8 Storage Spaces offering more options.</description></item><item><title>XBMC and Windows 8 on older hardware</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/13/xbmc-and-windows-8-on-older-hardware/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 10:07:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/13/xbmc-and-windows-8-on-older-hardware/</guid><description>Just wanted to note that older hardware works well with the new Windows 8 consumer preview. Since I had to change the hdd in my xbmc mediacenter I decided to give Windows 8 a spin on real hardware (not just virtual).
Hardware:
Gigabyte GA-MA78GPM-DS2H motherboard (AMD 780G +SB700 chipset) AMD 4850e dual core energy efficient cpu 250Gb hdd (all media is stored on a NAS) 6Gb RAM When I moved to a Full HD tv I found that I have to move away from XP to windows 7 in order to get decent hardware acceleration out of my integrated graphics.</description></item><item><title>Removed ntfs partition reappears</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/13/removed-ntfs-partition-reappears/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 08:16:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/13/removed-ntfs-partition-reappears/</guid><description>So, I was repartitioning a harddrive that used to be a windows disk. I removed the ntfs partition that was spanning the whole drive and created a linux layout instead (two linux partitions and one swap). After writing the partition table the first partition on the disk failed to format. Returning to fdisk I saw that the first partition was still of type NTFS. So I changed the type once more and wrote the partition table to disk.</description></item><item><title>Killall for windows :)</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/09/11/killall-for-windows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 08:11:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/09/11/killall-for-windows/</guid><description>Ever wanted to kill a process from the command line in windows? Here&amp;rsquo;s how:
If you know the name of a process to kill, for example firefox.exe, use the following command from a command prompt to end it:
taskkill /IM firefox.exe This will cause the program to terminate gracefully, asking for confirmation if there are unsaved changes. To forcefully kill the same process, add the /F option to the command line.</description></item><item><title>How to check if TRIM is enabled on your SSD</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/23/how-to-check-if-trim-is-enabled-on-your-ssd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2010 10:07:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/23/how-to-check-if-trim-is-enabled-on-your-ssd/</guid><description>God a fancy new drive? SSD maybe? TRIM support advertised? Well, here&amp;rsquo;s how you can check if TRIM support is actually enabled and working in your windows installation:
Start a command prompt window (WIN+R, type cmd and press enter)
In the command prompt window type the following:
fsutil behavior query disabledeletenotify You will get one of the following:
DisableDeleteNotify = 1 (Means that Windows TRIM commands are disabled) DisableDeleteNotify = 0 (Means that Windows TRIM commands are enabled)</description></item><item><title>Windows XP – prevent a user’s password from expiring</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/06/windows-xp-prevent-a-users-password-from-expiring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 09:54:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/06/windows-xp-prevent-a-users-password-from-expiring/</guid><description>One of my clients called be mecause every now and then his was bugged by Windows XP to change his password. This seemed weird as XP doesn&amp;rsquo;t do this by default. Probably it was set to expire by someone or by some friendly security suite.
Fortunately the solution for this expiring password problem is easy. You just need to tell Windows that you want your password to never expire. This is not necessarily a good practice, nevertheless if you want to, here is how you do it.</description></item><item><title>How to mount a windows share (samba) from the linux command line</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/24/how-to-mount-a-windows-share-samba-from-the-linux-command-line/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 18:03:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/24/how-to-mount-a-windows-share-samba-from-the-linux-command-line/</guid><description>As you know Linux does not use drive letters like Windows does. All files are organized under a big tree hierarchy. We use the mount command to mount partitions and this is the same command used to mount remote windows partition or windows shares.
Please note that you&amp;rsquo;ll need to know the following:
Windows username and password (the ones needed to access the share) The machine and share name. Something like //xpdesktop/pictures Have root access on the linux machine Login on your linux machine as root.</description></item><item><title>Old Soundblaster Live 5.1 on windows 7</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/20/old-soundblaster-live-5-1-on-windows-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 21:28:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/20/old-soundblaster-live-5-1-on-windows-7/</guid><description>I tried running Windows 7 on a machine that had a Creative Sound Blaster Live 5.1 card inside. Since the 5.1 is a decent card I see no reason to replace it just because windows 7 came along. Please note that these unofficial updated drivers also bring along Windows 64 bit support. A quick google search revealed this:
http://forums.creative.com/t5/Sound-Blaster/SB-Live-series-Support-Pack-1-5-08-09-2009/td-p/533861
Please note that this is an unofficial patch and that it has problems if your Windows 7 machine has more than 2 Gb of RAM.</description></item><item><title>Windows 7 small arrow icons for Desktop shortcuts</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/10/18/windows-7-small-arrow-icons-for-desktop-shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2009 20:21:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/10/18/windows-7-small-arrow-icons-for-desktop-shortcuts/</guid><description>Many guides found online will show you how to completely remove the arrow of the desktop shortcuts. If you, like me, preffer the smaller shortcut arrow icon that Windows XP has, as opposed to the big one Windows 7 proudly shows here&amp;rsquo;s what you have to d:
Start regedit (Alt+R, regedit.exe, enter)** **
Go to:
HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Microsoft Windows\CurrentVersion\Explorer\Shell Icons If Sell Icons is not there, under Explorer create the new key. (Right cklick, new key)</description></item><item><title>Small but useful Windows junk cleaner</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/19/small-but-useful/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 08:59:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/19/small-but-useful/</guid><description>I just stumbled upon a nice little utility. It&amp;rsquo;s called ATF Cleaner. What it does? What you always do when you clean up a computer or remove a virus: it cleans temporary folders, temporary internet files and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s what you basically do manually every time you start working on a computer with problems.
It&amp;rsquo;s small, fast and useful but as it&amp;rsquo;s always the case with utilities that erase files you should be careful.</description></item></channel></rss>