<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>password on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/password/</link><description>Recent content in password on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 10:45:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/password/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The difference between exclamation mark and asterisk in /etc/shadow</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/10/01/the-difference-between-exclamation-mark-and-asterisk-in-etcshadow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 10:45:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/10/01/the-difference-between-exclamation-mark-and-asterisk-in-etcshadow/</guid><description>So, with a terrible case of memory lapsus while wanting to disable password login for a user I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember what the difference between &amp;ldquo;!&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;*&amp;rdquo; is in the /etc/shadow file.
Well man 5 shadow to the rescue
Refer to **crypt**(3) for details on how this string is interpreted. If the password field contains some string that is not a valid result of **crypt**(3), for instance ! or *, the user will not be able to use a unix password to log in (but the user may log in the system by other means).</description></item><item><title>Windows XP – prevent a user’s password from expiring</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/06/windows-xp-prevent-a-users-password-from-expiring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 09:54:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/06/windows-xp-prevent-a-users-password-from-expiring/</guid><description>One of my clients called be mecause every now and then his was bugged by Windows XP to change his password. This seemed weird as XP doesn&amp;rsquo;t do this by default. Probably it was set to expire by someone or by some friendly security suite.
Fortunately the solution for this expiring password problem is easy. You just need to tell Windows that you want your password to never expire. This is not necessarily a good practice, nevertheless if you want to, here is how you do it.</description></item><item><title>Authentication problems with postfix, courier, mysql and virtual domains</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/03/15/authentication-problems-with-postfix-courier-mysql-and-virtual-domains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 20:54:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/03/15/authentication-problems-with-postfix-courier-mysql-and-virtual-domains/</guid><description>I outgrew my shared hosting and decided to go for a dedicated virtual server. I chose Linode but I will leave that for another article.
I decided to use postfix + courier + mysql and virtual domains for my mail setup. Everythig was configured fine and dandy according to the documentation. But I kept getting this in the logs:
Mar 6 13:54:42 saslauthd [5734]: pam_mysql - required option &amp;#34;db&amp;#34; is not set Mar 6 13:54:42 saslauthd [5734]: DEBUG: auth_pam: pam_authenticate failed: Error in service module Mar 6 13:54:42 saslauthd [5734]: do_auth : auth failure: [user=test@xxxxxxx.</description></item><item><title>How to recover a lost Joomla admin password</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/18/how-to-recover-a-lost-joomla-admin-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 19:32:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/18/how-to-recover-a-lost-joomla-admin-password/</guid><description>I administer a few Joomla sites so from time to time I discover that I lost the admin password for the one I hadn&amp;rsquo;t had to update for a long time. There is no way to find out what that password was because they are stored as a one way MD5 but since I usually use random characters anyway I reset the password with a new one. For that you need access to the mysql database of that Joomla site.</description></item><item><title>Recover your lost linux slackware root password</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/recover-your-lost-linux-slackware-root-password/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 13:31:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/recover-your-lost-linux-slackware-root-password/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m an avid Slackware user. It was the distro I started using back in &amp;lsquo;98 and, even if I tried and used many others I still like it the most. Anyways these rules apply to many other flavours of linux.
One of the problems I faced is needing to make changes on inherited machines that nobody knew the passwords for. So, if you face the same problem, or you simply forgot the root password because you usually use a normal user account here&amp;rsquo;s what you have to do to reset the password.</description></item></channel></rss>