<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ks0108 on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/ks0108/</link><description>Recent content in ks0108 on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 15:41:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/ks0108/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>bmp2h converter for ks0108 GLCD</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/01/bmp2h-converter-for-ks0108-glcd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 15:41:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/01/bmp2h-converter-for-ks0108-glcd/</guid><description>This is a converter I wrote with the graphics library for the PIC16F microcontrollers. Others work but this one works for sure.
If you want to see the source code (I&amp;rsquo;m not particulary proud of it 🙂 ) drop a comment and I&amp;rsquo;ll send it to you.
If the bitmap is smaller than 128×64 it will be left as is, if not it will be resized proportionally to 128×64.
You can set the name you want your variable to have and you can also set if you want the picture inverted or not.</description></item><item><title>KS0108 Graphics Library for PIC16F microcontrollers</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/01/ks0108-graphics-library-for-pic16f-microcontrollers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 15:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/01/ks0108-graphics-library-for-pic16f-microcontrollers/</guid><description>Not that I&amp;rsquo;m not happy with the default mikroC library for the KS0108 graphic displays, as I always I wanted something with the source available. Considering that I&amp;rsquo;m a beginner with microcontrolers having the source available to hack around is a very valuable learning tool.
The project is based on the source found here:
http://en.radzio.dxp.pl/ks0108/
The source is made pretty universal, still it took some work and modifications to have it working in mikroC.</description></item><item><title>Temperature graph on GLCD with EasyPic5</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/18/temperature-graph-on-glcd-with-easypic5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 17:17:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/18/temperature-graph-on-glcd-with-easypic5/</guid><description>This is a small project I did for school. I am using the easypic 5 board from mikroelectronica to display a linegraph of the temperature read every second by the DS1820 sensor and displays it on the KS0108 based GLCD. I am using the OneWire and GLCD libraries that come with the mikroC compiler.
I am using a PIC16F887 mounted on the board. You might need to adjust the code if you use a different microcontroler / development board.</description></item></channel></rss>