<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>memory on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/memory/</link><description>Recent content in memory on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 09:44:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/memory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Useful oneliner: check the memory usage of apache / httpd processes</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/10/19/useful-oneliner-check-the-memory-usage-of-apache-httpd-processes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 09:44:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/10/19/useful-oneliner-check-the-memory-usage-of-apache-httpd-processes/</guid><description>This is a handy one liner that reports the usage of the apache processes (apache2 on debian/ubunto or httpd in slackware, centos, etc)
ps -ylC httpd | awk &amp;#39;{x += $8;y += 1} END {print &amp;#34;Apache Memory Usage (MB): &amp;#34;x/1024; print &amp;#34;Average Proccess Size (MB): &amp;#34;x/((y-1)*1024)}&amp;#39;</description></item><item><title>Memory limits of various Windows versions</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/memory-limits-of-various-windows-versions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 21:02:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/memory-limits-of-various-windows-versions/</guid><description> Thinking of a memory upgrade? An operating system upgrade? Here&amp;rsquo;s a table from msdn stating the limits imposed by 32 and 64 bit editions of various Windows versions.
Physical Memory Limits: Windows 7 The following table specifies the limits on physical memory for Windows 7.
Version Limit in 32-bit Windows Limit in 64-bit Windows Windows Server 2003 with Service Pack 2 (SP2), Datacenter Edition 128 GB 64 GB with 4GT 2 TB Windows Server 2003 with Service Pack 2 (SP2), Enterprise Edition 64 GB 2 TB Windows Storage Server 2003, Enterprise Edition 8 GB Not applicable Windows Storage Server 2003 4 GB Not applicable Windows Server 2003 R2 Datacenter Edition Windows Server 2003 with Service Pack 1 (SP1), Datacenter Edition 128 GB 16 GB with 4GT 1 TB Windows Server 2003 R2 Enterprise Edition Windows Server 2003 with Service Pack 1 (SP1), Enterprise Edition 64 GB 16 GB with 4GT 1 TB Windows Server 2003 R2 Standard Edition Windows Server 2003, Standard Edition SP1 Windows Server 2003, Standard Edition SP2 4 GB 32 GB Windows Server 2003, Datacenter Edition 128 GB 16 GB with 4GT 512 GB Windows Server 2003, Enterprise Edition 32 GB 16 GB with 4GT 64 GB Windows Server 2003, Standard Edition 4 GB 16 GB Windows Server 2003, Web Edition 2 GB Not applicable Windows Small Business Server 2003 4 GB Not applicable Windows Compute Cluster Server 2003 Not applicable 32 GB Version Limit in 32-bit Windows Limit in 64-bit Windows Windows XP 4 GB 128 GB Windows XP Starter Edition 512 MB Not applicable Version Limit in 32-bit Windows Windows 2000 Professional 4 GB Windows 2000 Server 4 GB Windows 2000 Advanced Server 8 GB Windows 2000 Datacenter Server 32 GB</description></item></channel></rss>