<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>browser on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/browser/</link><description>Recent content in browser on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 17:00:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/browser/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Three browsers on a phone</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/01/three-browsers-on-a-phone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 17:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/01/three-browsers-on-a-phone/</guid><description>The current state of browsers available for the Symbian operating system are a proof that there isn&amp;rsquo;t such thing as a one size fits all._ ****_You have the default browser, opera mobile, opera mini, skyfire and some others. I have installed on my e71 nokia phone Opera Mobile 10 beta, Skyfire and of course the default browser.
I tried to settle on using just one but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t. If I want to watch some flash video online or browse a really heavy site Skyfire is really the only option.</description></item><item><title>The revolution – desktop like experience on your mobile devices</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/03/the-revolution-desktop-like-experience-on-your-mobile-devices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 17:03:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/03/the-revolution-desktop-like-experience-on-your-mobile-devices/</guid><description>Everytime a new mobile devices comes around or a new browser is announced all the news sites and blogs happily announce a revolution: the desktop like browsing experience on a mobile device. I remember when I researched a few reviews before buying my Nokia E71 phone that some reviewers complained about the qvga resolution of the device.
I can only say this cow bagles !
First of all there&amp;rsquo;s no way that you can cram the 19&amp;quot; plus experience of a normal desktop monitor on a 2.</description></item><item><title>Skyfire updated to v1.0</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/skyfire-updated-to-v10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 06:09:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/skyfire-updated-to-v10/</guid><description>Just wanted to let you know that Skyfire has updated it&amp;rsquo;s browser to v1.0
Update was smooth on my E71.
What&amp;rsquo;s new:
Thumbnail interaction. You can click links without zooming in. A change I welcome. Improved Zoom. Enhanced Navigation. iFrame handlin. Fast start. Another change I like. Reconnect to last state. Remember last connection (Symbian only).</description></item><item><title>What’s installed on my Nokia E71 and why.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/whats-installed-on-my-nokia-e71-and-why/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 09:37:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/whats-installed-on-my-nokia-e71-and-why/</guid><description>As you might have noticed I am very fond of open source or freeware software. I like the community and the development pace of such projects, and of course I am fond of the price. So, before watching another top 10 freeware list, here&amp;rsquo;s a list from someone who actually used the programs for months or years and uses them on a daily basis:
1. Home screen From left to right:</description></item></channel></rss>