<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>backup on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/backup/</link><description>Recent content in backup on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 10:16:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running gcp.py from cron</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/03/running-gcp-py-from-cron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 10:16:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/03/running-gcp-py-from-cron/</guid><description>On my backup server I run gcp.py from gdatacopier to backup my google docs. I had to fix two issues in order to get it to run from a bash script:
the PYTHONPATH had to be exported prior to running, or the script will fail because it requires gdata-python-client the LANG envronment has to be set otherwise it will spill the following error in the log (if you bother to log the output from cron that is, otherwise it will just not work and you won&amp;rsquo;t know why, because the script works fine when ran manually) Traceback (most recent call last): File &amp;#34;/usr/local/bin/gcp.</description></item><item><title>[Errno 32] Broken pipe in s3cmd</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/05/28/errno-32-broken-pipe-in-s3cmd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 17:21:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/05/28/errno-32-broken-pipe-in-s3cmd/</guid><description>In order to backup a bunch of servers I&amp;rsquo;m using s3cmd to backup files to a Amazon S3 account. s3cmd is a really nice tool as it works from the command line, does encryption on the fly and can use the https protocol for upload.
I used
s3cmd -configure and set everything up. The first error I got when I tried to test it was:
s3cmd put file.tar.gz s3://my_bucket_name/file.tar.gz
[Errno 32] Broken pipe and it tried throttling down and uploading again.</description></item><item><title>Setting up master-slave replication for mysql</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/30/setting-up-master-slave-replication-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 19:27:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/30/setting-up-master-slave-replication-for-mysql/</guid><description>So, I had to set-up master-slave replication. Here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it:
Why would one want to set-up this? Easy.
Spread the read load across multiple servers: you can use the MySQL master for writing (inserts, updates) and the slave(s) for reading (SELECT) This should speed up things nicely for your application.
Do the backups from the slave. You might have noticed that backing-up, especially big databases, slows things down. That happens because mysqldump locks tables as it reads them.</description></item></channel></rss>