<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 10:30:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Raspberry Pi A+ Nixie NTP Clock</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/01/27/raspberry-pi-a-nixie-ntp-clock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 10:30:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/01/27/raspberry-pi-a-nixie-ntp-clock/</guid><description>Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like a Nixie tube based clock. Even my wife loved it. Bonus points if it&amp;rsquo;s very accurate.
I had in my parts box, for a very long time now, the display PCB from an old PH-meter. Old enough that it was done using Rusian 74141 clones - K155ID1 nixie drivers - a lot of logic chips (decade counters, serial latches, etc) and nixie tubes. It was also wired in a way that defied logic.</description></item><item><title>Install blinkstick on Slacware</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/01/15/install-blinkstick-on-slacware/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 07:46:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/01/15/install-blinkstick-on-slacware/</guid><description>I recently built a blinkstick, a cool little device. Using it under linux is very easy using the command line, but I had some issues installing it under Slackware:
pip install blinkstick Downloading/unpacking blinkstick Downloading BlinkStick-0.7.0.tar.gz Running setup.py egg_info for package blinkstick Requirement already satisfied (use -upgrade to upgrade): grapefruit==0.1a3 in /usr/lib64/python2.7/site-packages (from blinkstick) Requirement already satisfied (use -upgrade to upgrade): webcolors in /usr/lib64/python2.7/site-packages (from blinkstick) Downloading/unpacking pyusb (from blinkstick) Could not find a version that satisfies the requirement pyusb (from blinkstick) (from versions: 1.</description></item><item><title>Tentakel on CentOS 6 / Python 2.6</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/09/11/tentakel-on-centos-6-python-2-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 10:25:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/09/11/tentakel-on-centos-6-python-2-6/</guid><description>You probably already know this old, unmaintained but incredibly useful software: tentakel. If not check it out, you might like it.
There are two issues we need to tackle:
1. Tentakel uses tpg but the bundled version is not compatible with python 2.6
Error thrown:
return self.lexer[start:stop] TypeError: object cannot be interpreted as an index The fix is to download this version of tpg from it&amp;rsquo;s developer: http://cdsoft.fr/tpg/TPG-3.1.2.tar.gz From this archive extract tpg.</description></item><item><title>Wake on LAN a machine using Python – WOL</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/wake-on-lan-a-machine-using-python-wol/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 21:50:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/wake-on-lan-a-machine-using-python-wol/</guid><description>This is something useful: code to wake up a machine on lan using python. Since python is available on most devices now (symbian, maemo, windows, linux and so on) it&amp;rsquo;s pretty usefull. So, if you have machines that you want to be able to start this is the code to do it. I found it floating on the internet but since it&amp;rsquo;s GPL I see no problem in posting it.</description></item></channel></rss>