<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>script on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/script/</link><description>Recent content in script on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 20:29:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/script/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple script to add multiple trackers to a torrent downloading in transmission</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/11/06/simple-script-to-add-multiple-trackers-to-a-torrent-downloading-in-transmission/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 20:29:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/11/06/simple-script-to-add-multiple-trackers-to-a-torrent-downloading-in-transmission/</guid><description>Sometime you might want to download some old or obscure distro that was once packaged as a torrent. But many times the tracker embeded in the torrent file has long been abandoned or it has no peers. But many other trackers might have cached your torrent and maybe those have seeds. So I wrote a quick and dirty script to get a list of online trackers from transmission.
#!/bin/bash TRANSMISSION_REMOTE=&amp;#39;/usr/bin/transmission-remote&amp;#39; # Below is a command that will generate a tracker # list with one tracker per line # i.</description></item><item><title>Remove duplicates from the current folder</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/09/04/remove-duplicates-from-the-current-folder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 12:01:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/09/04/remove-duplicates-from-the-current-folder/</guid><description>I needed today to remove duplicate files from a big folder (8Gb+, 10000+ files). I use the nice fdupes program written by Adrian Lopez
fdupes -rdN . Note the point after the parameters. That means to search inside the current folder. A path could be provided instead of it. The options are:
-r means search recursively -d means delete. use carefully and read the man page to understand what could go wrong!</description></item><item><title>Transmission start-up script for slackware.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/02/13/transmission-start-up-script-for-slackware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 08:54:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/02/13/transmission-start-up-script-for-slackware/</guid><description>I installed transmission on a headless server so I need it to start on boot. The included start-up script was dependent on start-stop-daemon that is mission on Slackware. The examples on the transmission forums were ok but would resulted in transmission running as root and I want it to run as a non-privileged user. So I modified an example script to read like this:
#!/bin/bash #Slackware startup deamon script # Name of Service NAME=&amp;#34;Transmission Daemon&amp;#34; # Command to run CMD=&amp;#34;/usr/bin/transmission-daemon&amp;#34; # Option to run with deamon # -a means from where to accept incoming connections, comma separated # you may want to add your local network if you have multiple clients OPTIONS=&amp;#34;-a 127.</description></item><item><title>Unpacking a .deb file (including scripts)</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/23/unpacking-a-deb-file-including-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 10:11:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/23/unpacking-a-deb-file-including-scripts/</guid><description>While attempting to install a deb package on a slackware system I wanted to check the install script that the package runs. I tried the deb2tgz utility but unfortunately that only left me the files in the package in a ready to install .tgz file.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to unpack a .deb to obtain both scripts and files:
cd /tmp/somefolder tar x somepackage.deb This leaves you with two files:
control.tar.gz and data.</description></item><item><title>DNS::ZoneParse has an undocumented $ORIGIN</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/11/02/dnszoneparse-has-an-undocumented-origin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 13:29:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/11/02/dnszoneparse-has-an-undocumented-origin/</guid><description>I was working writing a few scripts that should update a DNS zone file on the fly. I decided to use the DNS::ZoneParse perl module for convenience.
The example there is straightforward for changing MX records so I thought modifying it to change an A record should be a piece of cake. Right? Wrong!
For the love of it I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get my code to modify the record in question, it would always delete it.</description></item><item><title>Automatically sync photos from digikam to your mobile phone</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/22/automatically-sync-photos-from-digikam-to-your-mobile-phone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 08:10:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/22/automatically-sync-photos-from-digikam-to-your-mobile-phone/</guid><description>I shoot a lot of pictures. My collection keeps growing (for example ~90 Gb right now) and since last year I discovered the joy of using digikam to tag and organize them. I&amp;rsquo;m using the beta 2.0.0 version and use mysql to store it&amp;rsquo;s databases (as opposed to the default sqlite) as it&amp;rsquo;s easier to interact and backup. What I want is to carry some of those pictures with me, specifically on my phone.</description></item><item><title>Easily send mail from a bash script</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/03/18/easily-send-mail-from-a-bash-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 14:03:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/03/18/easily-send-mail-from-a-bash-script/</guid><description>Did you ever need to have e-mail&amp;rsquo;s sent from within a bash script? Maybe alert you of errors encountered? Me too.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an easy way on how to do it:
#!/bin/bash # email send script example # # subject of email SUBJECT=&amp;#34;BASH SAYS HELLO&amp;#34; # destination EMAIL=&amp;#34;user@yourdomain.com&amp;#34; # Email body EMAILMESSAGE=&amp;#34;/tmp/messagebody.txt&amp;#34; echo &amp;#34;Email sent from BASH&amp;#34; &amp;gt; $EMAILMESSAGE echo &amp;#34;Another text line&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $EMAILMESSAGE # send message using /bin/mail /bin/mail -s &amp;#34;$SUBJECT&amp;#34; &amp;#34;$EMAIL&amp;#34; &amp;lt; $EMAILMESSAGE Easy.</description></item><item><title>Rename all files in a folder from upper to lower case.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/02/12/rename-all-files-in-a-folder-from-upper-to-lower-case/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 10:49:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/02/12/rename-all-files-in-a-folder-from-upper-to-lower-case/</guid><description>Sometimes is needed to have all files in a folder in the same case. Here&amp;rsquo;s a small script to rename all files in the folder to lower case:
for i in *; do mv $i `echo $i | tr [:upper:] [:lower:]`; done</description></item><item><title>Export a MySQL database using the command line.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/02/02/export-a-mysql-database-using-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 07:16:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/02/02/export-a-mysql-database-using-the-command-line/</guid><description>Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s easier to just drop to the command line then browse for fancy tools like phpMyAdmin. This is useful, especially for quick jobs.
mysqldump -u user -ppassword your_database &amp;gt; database_backup.sql Of course you need to replace:
user - mysql username password - the password your_database - the database you want to backup Adding -h host.domain.com would allow to backup a remote mysql database from YOUR shell, something like this:</description></item></channel></rss>