<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>twitter on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/twitter/</link><description>Recent content in twitter on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 08:23:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use nagios to track and graph your twitter followers</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/20/use-nagios-to-track-and-graph-your-twitter-followers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 08:23:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/20/use-nagios-to-track-and-graph-your-twitter-followers/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Nagios to monitor servers and devices for years now. Lately as an exercise to learn more about nagios I installed a private instance that I use to monitor everything I can think of - from my personal servers to the number of hours we watch TV.
A nice use I found is to monitor the number of followers my twitter bots and personal account have. For that I wrote a custom plugin, available in my small repository of plugins at: https://github.</description></item><item><title>Graph the number of twitter followers using Nagios</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/09/08/graph-the-number-of-twitter-followers-using-nagios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 13:52:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/09/08/graph-the-number-of-twitter-followers-using-nagios/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m running a nagios instance on a home machine to monitor and graph all kinds of data. Among them I wanted a graph of the twitter followers of some twitter bots I built.
I needed a script to get this number and for now I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to bother using the API.
The script simply uses curl to get a public http page, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t use the API. Use it and call it like below:</description></item><item><title>A simple retweet bot using a collocated Raspberry PI</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/09/13/a-simple-retweet-bot-using-a-collocated-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 08:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/09/13/a-simple-retweet-bot-using-a-collocated-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>I have a Raspberry PI freely collocated by the nice people at pcextreme. Being a Jolla fan I found a new use for it. I made a Retweet bot that retweets everything #Jolla.
It&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple. First you need to define your new twitter app here. Install on your raspberry the tweepy twitter python library. Warning usually it would be as easy as pip install tweepy but the current version has a bug which means you have to install a patched version of tweepy found here: git clone https://github.</description></item><item><title>I’m not using Gravity for Twitter access on my phone</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/14/im-not-using-gravity-for-twitter-access-on-my-phone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 13:06:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/08/14/im-not-using-gravity-for-twitter-access-on-my-phone/</guid><description>Even though I like Gravity a lot, I chose a simpler FREEWARE symbian native application as a client for Twitter - Tweets60:
It&amp;rsquo;s simple, fast, and has access point prioritization built in.
It may not be as feature full as Gravity, but it&amp;rsquo;s free - so you can&amp;rsquo;t argue there. You can write your tweets, follow others and click links and more. Even more I find it faster than Gravity. Of course if you need or want to be able to upload pictures and other advanced features that Tweet60 misses for now you&amp;rsquo;ll need to shell out the (modest) price of Gravity.</description></item><item><title>What’s installed on my Nokia E71 and why.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/whats-installed-on-my-nokia-e71-and-why/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 09:37:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/whats-installed-on-my-nokia-e71-and-why/</guid><description>As you might have noticed I am very fond of open source or freeware software. I like the community and the development pace of such projects, and of course I am fond of the price. So, before watching another top 10 freeware list, here&amp;rsquo;s a list from someone who actually used the programs for months or years and uses them on a daily basis:
1. Home screen From left to right:</description></item></channel></rss>