<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>n900 on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/n900/</link><description>Recent content in n900 on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 20:45:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/n900/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Disable charging of a Nokia N900 while USB connected.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/05/16/disable-charging-of-a-nokia-n900-while-usb-connected/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 20:45:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/05/16/disable-charging-of-a-nokia-n900-while-usb-connected/</guid><description>One of the joys of having a hackable computer serving as a phone is that you can do stuff which have no &amp;ldquo;option&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;settings&amp;rdquo;. Recently I wanted to see if I can connect it to an Android tablet (Samsung Galaxy Tab 10.1). I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Too bad as I could really use the extra 32Gb the n900 has to offer. It would connect but the tablet disconnects it as soon as the phone tries to start charging.</description></item><item><title>Concatenate multiple *.vcf files into one for importing into gMail</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/12/08/concatenate-multiple-vcf-files-into-one-for-importing-into-gmail/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 13:46:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/12/08/concatenate-multiple-vcf-files-into-one-for-importing-into-gmail/</guid><description>I have a secondary phone that is running Android. My main phone is still a Nokia N900 for which I gave up trying to sync contacts with gmail. Two options basically exist for n900 none of which works for me:
using MFE which works from time to time use syncevolution which invariably screws my contacts on the n900 (I guess google&amp;rsquo;s implementation of syncml or exchange support is dubious at best) So I devised a third.</description></item><item><title>Automatically sync photos from digikam to your mobile phone</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/22/automatically-sync-photos-from-digikam-to-your-mobile-phone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 08:10:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/22/automatically-sync-photos-from-digikam-to-your-mobile-phone/</guid><description>I shoot a lot of pictures. My collection keeps growing (for example ~90 Gb right now) and since last year I discovered the joy of using digikam to tag and organize them. I&amp;rsquo;m using the beta 2.0.0 version and use mysql to store it&amp;rsquo;s databases (as opposed to the default sqlite) as it&amp;rsquo;s easier to interact and backup. What I want is to carry some of those pictures with me, specifically on my phone.</description></item></channel></rss>