<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>android on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/android/</link><description>Recent content in android on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 11:53:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[updated] List of Humble Bundle Games that work on the Sailfish OS Jolla Phone</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/01/03/list-of-humble-bundle-games-that-work-on-the-sailfish-os-jolla-phone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 11:53:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/01/03/list-of-humble-bundle-games-that-work-on-the-sailfish-os-jolla-phone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Being and old time Maemo fan I went and preordered the Jolla phone as soon as I could (March 2013 IIRC) and I&amp;rsquo;ve been happily playing with it ever since I got it. I like to play the occasional game on the go and so I bought many of the bundles that humblebundle offered. Happily they also offer an android application that functions like a store - you can see all the games you bought and download/install/update them. Follow &lt;a href="http://www.humblebundle.com/app">these directions to install the Humble Bundle&lt;/a> app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read bellow is a list of the games I own and as I get time to test them I will update the status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Silly Android contact merging</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/06/07/silly-android-contact-merging/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 10:36:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/06/07/silly-android-contact-merging/</guid><description>So, for now my beloved n900 is in the service dead, so I started organizing contacts on the Android phone I have. First thing I did was to merge contacts (for example joining Jon Doe&amp;rsquo;s contact from google-phonebook, facebook, skype and so on)
I&amp;rsquo;m used to doing this for years now as the old n900 but I noticed this strange behaviour with some of my frinds who use fake names /nicknames for skype or facebook, etc.</description></item><item><title>Concatenate multiple *.vcf files into one for importing into gMail</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/12/08/concatenate-multiple-vcf-files-into-one-for-importing-into-gmail/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 13:46:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/12/08/concatenate-multiple-vcf-files-into-one-for-importing-into-gmail/</guid><description>I have a secondary phone that is running Android. My main phone is still a Nokia N900 for which I gave up trying to sync contacts with gmail. Two options basically exist for n900 none of which works for me:
using MFE which works from time to time use syncevolution which invariably screws my contacts on the n900 (I guess google&amp;rsquo;s implementation of syncml or exchange support is dubious at best) So I devised a third.</description></item></channel></rss>