<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>xp on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/xp/</link><description>Recent content in xp on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 09:54:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/xp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows XP – prevent a user’s password from expiring</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/06/windows-xp-prevent-a-users-password-from-expiring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 09:54:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/06/windows-xp-prevent-a-users-password-from-expiring/</guid><description>One of my clients called be mecause every now and then his was bugged by Windows XP to change his password. This seemed weird as XP doesn&amp;rsquo;t do this by default. Probably it was set to expire by someone or by some friendly security suite.
Fortunately the solution for this expiring password problem is easy. You just need to tell Windows that you want your password to never expire. This is not necessarily a good practice, nevertheless if you want to, here is how you do it.</description></item><item><title>What I add to a fresh install of Windows XP</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/01/what-i-add-to-a-fresh-install-of-windows-xp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 08:30:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/01/what-i-add-to-a-fresh-install-of-windows-xp/</guid><description>Yes, yes, I know, Windows 7 is all the rage today. But, XP is still widely used and for now is the operating system I need to install on 90% of the cases. Of course first I install Windows XP, then the pc&amp;rsquo;s drivers and utilities, then I add whatever commercial software the client uses. After that, from case to case I always add some of the following:
Security If it&amp;rsquo;s a home user that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a paid antivirus solution I install AVG free or Avast Home edition.</description></item></channel></rss>