<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>n800 on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/n800/</link><description>Recent content in n800 on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 19:57:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/n800/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Error getting the post list – Maemo WordPy</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/error-getting-the-post-list-maemo-wordpy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 19:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/error-getting-the-post-list-maemo-wordpy/</guid><description>Today I tried again installing and configuring WordPy for Maemo on my Nokia N800 internet tablet. Since I can blog from my mobile phone I wanted to have a wordpress blog client on my tablet as well.
I configured everything correctly but I kept getting the _Error getting the post list message everytime I wanted to refresh the posts list. I browsed the forum, tried everything than I realized the only difference between configurations posted on the forum and mine: http:// was missing from my Blog URL field in the configuration.</description></item><item><title>N800/N810 tablet as a Canon camera remote</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/27/n800n810-tablet-as-a-canon-camera-remote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 09:37:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/27/n800n810-tablet-as-a-canon-camera-remote/</guid><description>This post is also on the talk.maemo.org forum, but I decided to host it here too.
N800 camera remote control I followed a thread regarding the port of gphoto for the Nokia Internet Tablets. Unfortunately gphoto never got me further than list the photos in the camera and then hang and reboot.
Well then I noticed Eostimesync.
Eostimesync is a nice utility that syncs the time of your camera to the time of the n800.</description></item></channel></rss>