<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>php on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/php/</link><description>Recent content in php on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 09:20:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding pcntl_fork support on a cpanel server</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/02/01/adding-pcntl_fork-support-on-a-cpanel-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 09:20:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/02/01/adding-pcntl_fork-support-on-a-cpanel-server/</guid><description>A php application on a cpanel server kept throwing this:
Fatal error: Call to undefined function pcntl_fork() in /path/blah.php on line 5 The fix requires recompiling php with -enable-pcntl Fortunately cpanel offers the Easy Apache script. The bad part is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an option for pcntl. So you have to specify it as a custom compile time option. Edit (or create - for PHP5) and add /var/cpanel/easy/apache/rawopts/all_php5
-enable-pcntl On one line</description></item><item><title>Error noticed in Joomla site apache logs</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/10/27/error-noticed-in-joomla-site-apache-logs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 17:50:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/10/27/error-noticed-in-joomla-site-apache-logs/</guid><description>Browsing trough my web logs I found the following error in the apache error log of a Joomla site:
[Mon Oct 17 13:49:16 2011] [error] [client aaa.aaa.aaa.aaa] PHP Notice: Array to string conversion in aaa/libraries/joomla/html/parameter.php on line 83 One suggestion found online was:
Edit parameters.php and change the line 83 as follows:
Before:
if (trim( $data )) { After:
if ($data) { But modifying core joomla files isn&amp;rsquo;t such a hot idea as one user notices.</description></item><item><title>Web interface for Zabbix didn’t load</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/08/18/web-interface-for-zabbix-didnt-load/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2011 07:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/08/18/web-interface-for-zabbix-didnt-load/</guid><description>I was installing today Zabbix on a CentOS 5.6 machine and hit the following error when trying to load the PHP Web Interface:
PHP Fatal error: Call to undefined function bcscale() in /var/www/zabbix/include/defines.inc.php on line 797 The fix was one package install away:
yum -y install php-bcmath</description></item><item><title>Add php APC and UploadProgress support to CentOS</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/08/03/add-php-apc-and-uploadprogress-support-to-centos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 08:25:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/08/03/add-php-apc-and-uploadprogress-support-to-centos/</guid><description>I was playing today with some file uploading scripts and noticed that they require one of the two in order to be able to display a progress bar.
Those are the steps required to enabled both of them on centos:
yum install php-pear php-devel httpd-devel pcre-devel pecl install apc pecl install uploadprogress Than I created in /etc/php.d/ the following files:
; provides upload progress, installed using pecl extension=apc.so apc.rfc1867=1 and</description></item><item><title>Make Joomla 1.0 work with PHP 5.3</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/23/make-joomla-1-0-work-with-php-5-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 10:43:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/23/make-joomla-1-0-work-with-php-5-3/</guid><description>With the recent posts regarding resurrecting old stuff, recently I had to resurrect a Joomla 1.0 site. Soon enough I discovered that the home page doesn&amp;rsquo;t display correctly. No errors, just lots of white space :). The problem is that Joomla 1.0 is not really made for PHP 5.3. Of course I could have started a virtual machine with the right environment but I wanted it running along some newer sites.</description></item><item><title>Akismet troubles traced back to DNS issues.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/02/akismet-troubles-traced-back-to-dns-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 05:50:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/02/akismet-troubles-traced-back-to-dns-issues/</guid><description>My API key for Akismet was suddenly unconfirmed by reason of not being able to reach akismet.com My provider had indeed troubles with their primary DNS so I switched to the google public one. (8.8.8.8). This is a server not a browsing machine so I don&amp;rsquo;t have any privacy worries.
Long storry short, I changed the DNS and expected the problem to go away. Next day I was happy to find out that it didn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>Uploading big files via php</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/02/11/uploading-big-files-php/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 09:43:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/02/11/uploading-big-files-php/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m updating a site for a client that only has file access to his hosting account via a php file manager (extPlorer for Joomla to be precise). He needed uploaded a few flash videos (in excess of 15 Mb each) but extPlorer stated that the file limit for php was set to 8 Mb.
I already knew that .htaccess overrides were allowed since I used .htaccess to enable a seo component for the site.</description></item><item><title>New menu items don’t appear in Joomla 1.5.14</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/03/new-menu-items-dont-appear-in-joomla-1-5-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 10:27:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/03/new-menu-items-dont-appear-in-joomla-1-5-14/</guid><description>I was configuring a Joomla installation for a client today and stumbled upon this little problem. No matter how I tried, new menu items refused to appear. Not only in the front-end, but they were missing in the back-end too. I checked to see, but the PHP settings were all correct. Then I noticed that the WAMP installation used PHP 5.3.0. A quick look on the Joomla Forums confirmed that Joomla has problems with this version of PHP.</description></item><item><title>Custom csv export from virtuemart</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/04/custom-csv-export-from-virtuemart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 09:11:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/04/custom-csv-export-from-virtuemart/</guid><description>One of my clients needed a custom feed of his virtuemart products. I did a quick google check and nothing came up, so I decided to write my own. Please note that I&amp;rsquo;m not a programmer and I bet it can be done faster, better and more elegant, still this works, so &amp;hellip;
&amp;lt;?php // Please note those was developed for a Joomla 1.5 installation // www.sgvulcan.com $host = &amp;#34;localhost&amp;#34;; //database location $user = &amp;#34;user&amp;#34;; //database username $pass = &amp;#34;pass&amp;#34;; //database password $db_name = &amp;#34;database&amp;#34;; //database name $wtxt=&amp;#34;; //database connection $link = mysql_connect($host, $user, $pass); mysql_select_db($db_name); $myFile = &amp;#34;product_export.</description></item></channel></rss>