<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>book on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/book/</link><description>Recent content in book on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 18:09:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Another free e-book about Microcontrollers</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/02/another-free-e-book-about-microcontrollers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 18:09:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/12/02/another-free-e-book-about-microcontrollers/</guid><description>Mikroelektronica, beign the nice guys they are released another free e-book about programming PIC microcontrollers this time it&amp;rsquo;s about programming in C. The title is, unsurprisingly:
PIC Microcontrollers - Programming in C
What are microcontrollers, anyway? Electronics built in one single chip capable of controlling a small submarine, a crane or an elevator… It’s up to you to decide what you want them to do and dump a program containing appropriate instructions into the chip.</description></item><item><title>Grokking the Gimp</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/25/grokking-the-gimp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 08:52:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/25/grokking-the-gimp/</guid><description>Since we were talking Grokking the Gimp is a free book by Carey Bunks. It&amp;rsquo;s an advanced book covering A LOT of what you can do with Gimp.
For any of you who are at least a little bit interested in graphics Gimp should already be on your radar. I know that Adobe Photoshop is more advanced, but I also realized working with both that for at least 90% of the tasks (and for my webdesign and graphics design needs 100%) is good enough.</description></item><item><title>A free e-book from Texas Instruments – LED Reference Design Cookbook</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/23/a-free-e-book-from-texas-instruments-led-reference-design-cookbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 12:23:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/23/a-free-e-book-from-texas-instruments-led-reference-design-cookbook/</guid><description>The guys over at Make were kind enough to signal this free e-book from Texas instruments.
It is a 41-page &amp;ldquo;cookbook&amp;rdquo; of circuit designs and application notes for TI&amp;rsquo;s LED-related components. Makes for an interesting read even if you don&amp;rsquo;t use TI&amp;rsquo;s stuff.
What&amp;rsquo;s inside: Small LCD Backlight with Digital and PWM Dimming Small LCD Backlight from LDO Medium-Size LCD Backlight Large-LCD Backlight Driver Constant Current Driver with PFC Boost Controller with PFC Replacement for Standard Lightbulb 25-Watt Dimmable Driver with PFC 100-Watt, Constant-Current, Non-Isolated Driver with PFC 110-Watt, Constant-Current, Isolated Driver with PFC 10-Watt, Green-Mode PWM LED Driver Wireless-Controlled Triple LED Drive Low Voltage Buck Boost for LED Torch Boost Driver with Integrated Power Switch Nonsynchronous Boost LED Driver Wide Input DC Voltage Range SEPIC Driver 3-Watt Solar Lantern LED Reference Design Cookbook [PDF]</description></item><item><title>A free book about PIC Microcontrollers</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/a-free-book-about-pic-microcontrollers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 11:22:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/a-free-book-about-pic-microcontrollers/</guid><description>As you might have noticed from my posts I am always in for a free lunch.
So, this would be free lunch for your brain. Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t use or plan to use Mikroelektronika products you might want to know that they have a free book about PIC microcontrolers on their website: here.
It&amp;rsquo;s not tied up to any of their development systems but it does focus on the PIC16F887, and even if the English used is not the best possible it still gets the job done.</description></item><item><title>Star Trek S.C.E.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/star-trek-s-c-e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 09:58:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/star-trek-s-c-e/</guid><description>Have Tech, Will Travel is an anthology collecting the first four books from Pocket Books&amp;rsquo; original eBook series about the Starfleet Corps of Engineers, depicting the missions of a rapid response team of SCE taking place during the 2370s. Several canon characters and concepts were included in the stories, but with new details not mentioned in televised Star Trek of the era.
I have recently finished reading every novel in the Star Trek S.</description></item><item><title>Computer Networks, Fourth Edition by Andrew S. Tanenbaum</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/computer-networks-fourth-edition-by-andrew-s-tanenbaum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 08:34:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/computer-networks-fourth-edition-by-andrew-s-tanenbaum/</guid><description>To most of you this is probably old news, but if you didn&amp;rsquo;t read it go out buy a copy and read it ! I thought I knew pretty much about networks, but after I read this book I knew a lot more. There&amp;rsquo;s no way around it. If you are involved with computer networks this is a must.
It&amp;rsquo;s clearly written, simple explained, and one of the technical books I have enjoyed the most.</description></item></channel></rss>