<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>network on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/network/</link><description>Recent content in network on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 08:07:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speed-up X over ssh</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/01/31/speed-up-x-over-ssh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 08:07:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/01/31/speed-up-x-over-ssh/</guid><description>Even though I run a pretty fast network and vpn at home I still have the occasional hiccup running demanding applications (i.e. digikam) at home.
A few simple options can speed up X considerably. Connecting with the following parametters will enable a fast encryption cipher and also enables compression:
ssh -X -C -c blowfish-cbc,arcfour user@host.example.com Of course you can make this permanent by adding the following to /etc/ssh/ssh_config or even better only for the specific host in ~/.</description></item><item><title>Log dropped packets using CentOS Firewall</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/23/log-dropped-packets-using-centos-firewall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 07:16:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/23/log-dropped-packets-using-centos-firewall/</guid><description>Please take care modifying your firewall. If you don&amp;rsquo;t understand what&amp;rsquo;s being done here you may lock yourself out of your machine. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned 🙂 !
In order to log dropped packets on the INPUT chain I replaced this:
-A INPUT -i eth0 -j REJECT -reject-with icmp-host-prohibited with this
-N LOGDROP -A LOGDROP -i eth0 -j LOG -A LOGDROP -i eth0 -j REJECT -reject-with icmp-host-prohibited -A INPUT -i eth0 -j LOGDROP Of course you can use DROP instead of REJECT -reject-with icmp-host-prohibited</description></item><item><title>Apache 2.2 will not serve corectly from CIFS mounted share</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/27/apache-2-2-will-not-serve-corectly-from-cifs-mounted-share/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 09:09:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/27/apache-2-2-will-not-serve-corectly-from-cifs-mounted-share/</guid><description>I have a home server I use for all kinds of stuff when I&amp;rsquo;m away. I have set it up recently so that it can serve a folder mounted over the network from a Windows machine.
And this is where the fun started!
The folders and files appear correctly, I can navigate and I can download them. Only that the files, even if apparently having the same size are corrupted. I checked the FollowSymLinks and as expected was set as required.</description></item><item><title>Network interface bonding in Slackware (version 13.1)</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/20/network-interface-bonding-in-slackware-version-13-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 11:26:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/20/network-interface-bonding-in-slackware-version-13-1/</guid><description>A backup NAS I set up for a client had some problems - i.e. from time to time the network card would hang forcing a reboot (the machine was headless). The disks in the nas are RAID 1 providing redundancy in case of failure. We wanted the same with the network. So, nothing easier than to install a second network card and set up bonding.
What is network bonding? Bonding is the same as port trunking.</description></item></channel></rss>