<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>slackware on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/slackware/</link><description>Recent content in slackware on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 07:28:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/slackware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>mono 3.10 on slackware 64 bit</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/03/24/mono-3-10-on-slackware-64-bit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 07:28:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/03/24/mono-3-10-on-slackware-64-bit/</guid><description>I installed mono using sbopkg and found the following issue while trying to run keepass:
System.TypeInitializationException: An exception was thrown by the type initializer for Mono.Unix.Native.Syscall -&amp;gt; System.DllNotFoundException: /usr/lib/libMonoPosixHelper.so at (wrapper managed-to-native) Mono.Unix.Native.Syscall:get_at_fdcwd () at Mono.Unix.Native.Syscall..cctor () [0x00000] in &amp;lt;filename unknown&amp;gt;:0 - End of inner exception stack trace - The fix was to edit [cci]/etc/mono/config[/cci] and remove the [cci]/usr/lib/[/cci] path from the [cci]libMonoPosixHelper.so[/cci] definition so that it looks like this:</description></item><item><title>Black levels tool output in digikam after upgrading to 2.6</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/05/10/black-levels-tool-output-in-digikam-after-upgrading-to-2-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 18:30:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/05/10/black-levels-tool-output-in-digikam-after-upgrading-to-2-6/</guid><description>I tested the 2.6-rc version of digikam and found that the levels tool offers a black window instead of proper output.
First I thought it&amp;rsquo;s a 2.6 issue so I reverted to my 2.5.0 stable version. No luck. I then thought it&amp;rsquo;s because some updates I ran for Slackware (I&amp;rsquo;m using current64) Not having any luck I opened a bug, thankfully the digikam developers were quick to reply: https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=299755
To be short the issue will be fixed for 2.</description></item><item><title>Transmission start-up script for slackware.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/02/13/transmission-start-up-script-for-slackware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 08:54:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/02/13/transmission-start-up-script-for-slackware/</guid><description>I installed transmission on a headless server so I need it to start on boot. The included start-up script was dependent on start-stop-daemon that is mission on Slackware. The examples on the transmission forums were ok but would resulted in transmission running as root and I want it to run as a non-privileged user. So I modified an example script to read like this:
#!/bin/bash #Slackware startup deamon script # Name of Service NAME=&amp;#34;Transmission Daemon&amp;#34; # Command to run CMD=&amp;#34;/usr/bin/transmission-daemon&amp;#34; # Option to run with deamon # -a means from where to accept incoming connections, comma separated # you may want to add your local network if you have multiple clients OPTIONS=&amp;#34;-a 127.</description></item><item><title>Make sensors report temperature on slackware64-current with an Intel I7 2600k</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/27/make-sensors-report-temperature-on-slackware64-current-with-an-intel-i7-2600k/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 20:01:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/27/make-sensors-report-temperature-on-slackware64-current-with-an-intel-i7-2600k/</guid><description>For some reasons the required modules don&amp;rsquo;t get loaded. Add the following to /etc/rc.d/rc.modules right above the line reading ### Mouse support:
### by SV for i2600k temperature /sbin/modprobe coretemp /sbin/modprobe pkgtemp Now sensors report the temperatures.</description></item><item><title>Unpacking a .deb file (including scripts)</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/23/unpacking-a-deb-file-including-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 10:11:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/23/unpacking-a-deb-file-including-scripts/</guid><description>While attempting to install a deb package on a slackware system I wanted to check the install script that the package runs. I tried the deb2tgz utility but unfortunately that only left me the files in the package in a ready to install .tgz file.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to unpack a .deb to obtain both scripts and files:
cd /tmp/somefolder tar x somepackage.deb This leaves you with two files:
control.tar.gz and data.</description></item><item><title>Compiling audacious 3.1</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/11/22/compiling-audacious-3-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 09:18:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/11/22/compiling-audacious-3-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of classic media players (audacious, xmms, the old winamp, etc.) That&amp;rsquo;s why I wanted today to complile the latest version of audacious (3.1) for my slackware laptop. Since the audacious build scripts are kind enough to provide make uninstall I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother with package builds, I simply compiled the stock source.
BTW that required upgrading libmowgli (got one from slacky). Audacious compiled succesfully but for audacious-plugins configure refused to run:</description></item><item><title>Network interface bonding in Slackware (version 13.1)</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/20/network-interface-bonding-in-slackware-version-13-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 11:26:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/07/20/network-interface-bonding-in-slackware-version-13-1/</guid><description>A backup NAS I set up for a client had some problems - i.e. from time to time the network card would hang forcing a reboot (the machine was headless). The disks in the nas are RAID 1 providing redundancy in case of failure. We wanted the same with the network. So, nothing easier than to install a second network card and set up bonding.
What is network bonding? Bonding is the same as port trunking.</description></item><item><title>Akonadi is not starting, refuses to run as root (Slackware 13.0/13.1/13.37/current installation).</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/09/08/akonadi-is-not-starting-refuses-to-run-as-root-slackware-13-013-113-37current-installation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2009 18:10:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/09/08/akonadi-is-not-starting-refuses-to-run-as-root-slackware-13-013-113-37current-installation/</guid><description>Well, I am having fun lately with the latest incarnation of the Slackware Linux distribution. Like I said before I am a slacker, and I like Slackware a lot. In a way it&amp;rsquo;s nice that some things don&amp;rsquo;t work out of the box. You get to know how they work.
Well, after my first startx I was greeted by a message stating that Akonadi failed to start / Akonadi fails to start.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Mysql in Slackware 13.0</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/09/07/configuring-mysql-in-slackware-13-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 16:46:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/09/07/configuring-mysql-in-slackware-13-0/</guid><description>Slackware 13 has still the same unintuitive style with some things - i.e. akonadi doesn&amp;rsquo;t start in kde and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t say why, and so on.
One of the problems you will encounter is that Mysql doesn&amp;rsquo;t start. Yes, if you look in /usr/doc/mysql&amp;hellip; you will find the reason.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what you have to do:
Run
mysql_install_db This will configure the default databases mysql needs to function. Now, this is where you would normally start mysql using /etc/rc.</description></item><item><title>Slackware 13 is here</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/09/01/slackware-13-is-here/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 07:48:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/09/01/slackware-13-is-here/</guid><description>Yupeee, a new toy. Slacware 13.0 is out, with an official and in sync 64bit version too. Finally upgraded to KDE 4.2.x.
Get yours while it&amp;rsquo;s hot. And don&amp;rsquo;t forget to support the project by buying the dvd&amp;rsquo;s from the Slackware store.
Have fun!</description></item><item><title>Recover your lost linux slackware root password</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/recover-your-lost-linux-slackware-root-password/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 13:31:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/28/recover-your-lost-linux-slackware-root-password/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m an avid Slackware user. It was the distro I started using back in &amp;lsquo;98 and, even if I tried and used many others I still like it the most. Anyways these rules apply to many other flavours of linux.
One of the problems I faced is needing to make changes on inherited machines that nobody knew the passwords for. So, if you face the same problem, or you simply forgot the root password because you usually use a normal user account here&amp;rsquo;s what you have to do to reset the password.</description></item><item><title>Getting sound to work on an old Deskpro EN and Slackware 12.2</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/03/getting-sound-to-work-on-an-old-deskpro-and-slackware-122/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 14:08:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/03/getting-sound-to-work-on-an-old-deskpro-and-slackware-122/</guid><description>I was trying to get rid of the separate sound card in an old Compaq Deskpro En (Pentium III) I use on a jukebox project. Alsa-conf would only detect some weird isa-pnp card that did not work. After searching a bit I found out that the card is an ESS 1869 and is not autodetected. Reading on the alsa website I found that these are the settings that work:
(set in /etc/modprobe.</description></item></channel></rss>