<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>optimize on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/optimize/</link><description>Recent content in optimize on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 08:07:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/optimize/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speed-up X over ssh</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/01/31/speed-up-x-over-ssh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 08:07:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/01/31/speed-up-x-over-ssh/</guid><description>Even though I run a pretty fast network and vpn at home I still have the occasional hiccup running demanding applications (i.e. digikam) at home.
A few simple options can speed up X considerably. Connecting with the following parametters will enable a fast encryption cipher and also enables compression:
ssh -X -C -c blowfish-cbc,arcfour user@host.example.com Of course you can make this permanent by adding the following to /etc/ssh/ssh_config or even better only for the specific host in ~/.</description></item><item><title>Optimize Firefox’s sqlite databases</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/08/07/optimize-firefoxs-sqlite-databases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 11:51:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/08/07/optimize-firefoxs-sqlite-databases/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a handy one-liner to tune a bit your Firefox:
for file in ~/.mozilla/firefox/*/*.sqlite; do sqlite3 $file &amp;#39;VACUUM;&amp;#39;;done What this does ie optimize every sqlite database in your account&amp;rsquo;s profiles. You can even add this line to a script to start on boot or by cron. Worth noting that Firefox should probably not run while you do this.</description></item><item><title>Optimizing all mysql tables (from all databases)</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/10/04/optimizing-all-mysql-tables-from-all-databases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 06:44:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/10/04/optimizing-all-mysql-tables-from-all-databases/</guid><description>You want to optimize mysql tables from time to time in order to reduce fragmentation. Here&amp;rsquo;s an easy way to do it automatically (put it in a script and run it from cron for example)
mysqlcheck -Aop -h hostname -u user -pPASSWORD What all those mean:
-all-databases, -A; Check all tables in all databases. This is the same as using the -databases option and naming all the databases on the command line.</description></item></channel></rss>