<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tech on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in tech on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 14:38:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Roll Your Own Tailscale MagicDNS Using pfSense and Unbound</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/12/09/roll-your-own-tailscale-magicdns-using-pfsense-and-unbound/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 14:38:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/12/09/roll-your-own-tailscale-magicdns-using-pfsense-and-unbound/</guid><description>The Why First question that would come to mind is why bother ? Tailscale implements a perfectly usable MagicDNS feature. Well there are a few reasons I quickly discovered after telling myself &amp;ldquo;Looks great, let&amp;rsquo;s enable it&amp;rdquo;:
Even if the issue is closed I still very often get DNS issues in Android if Tailscale with MagicDNS is active. When in the &amp;ldquo;home network&amp;rdquo; if tailscale is not active you have to remember two URLs: device.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu 22.04 Dislikes RSA Keys</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/06/18/ubuntu-22-04-dislikes-rsa-keys/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 14:01:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/06/18/ubuntu-22-04-dislikes-rsa-keys/</guid><description>I wrote in a past article about how I&amp;rsquo;m setting up Hetzner dedicated servers with full disk encryption even if they miss an ikvm and why Debian 10 machines require a RSA key for this.
But since I switched one of my workstations to Ubuntu 22.04 I was unable to login using this RSA key. Running ssh with debug enabled showed the likely culprit:
debug1: Offering public key: /home/user/.ssh/id_rsa debug1: send_pubkey_test: no mutual signature algorithm The message sent me on the right track, Ubuntu 22.</description></item><item><title>Full Disk Encryption on Hetzner Dedicated and Debian 10 Woes</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/06/18/full-disk-encryption-on-hetzner-dedicated-and-debian-10-woes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:41:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2022/06/18/full-disk-encryption-on-hetzner-dedicated-and-debian-10-woes/</guid><description>As absolutely nobody knows or uses I maintain an ansible role that can setup a Debian or Ubuntu machine with full disk encryption on Hetzner Robot (baremetal dedicated machines). But wait, you shout, Hetzner usually runs consumer grade stuff without kvm&amp;rsquo;s - how do you enter your password at bootime. Easy, the role sets up a minimal boot environment with a dropbear ssh server where you can login and do cryptroot-unlock.</description></item><item><title>Oracle complains about long identifier on simple operations.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/03/25/oracle-complains-about-long-identifier-on-simple-operations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 12:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/03/25/oracle-complains-about-long-identifier-on-simple-operations/</guid><description>Soo,
I&amp;rsquo;m going head first into the oracle db world. I was trying to create an spfile from the pfile and of course it didn&amp;rsquo;t work:
SQL&amp;gt; create spfile from pfile=&amp;#34;/oracle/app/product/12.1.0/dbhome_1/dbs/initORCL.ora&amp;#34;; create spfile from pfile=&amp;#34;/oracle/app/product/12.1.0/dbhome_1/dbs/initORCL.ora&amp;#34; * ERROR at line 1: ORA-00972: identifier is too long The reason is simple enough, you have to use single quotes instead of double quotes. But it took me a while to find out this so here it is for all other beginners.</description></item><item><title>Errors in mail.log from nagios check_ssmtp</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/03/25/errors-in-mail-log-from-nagios-check_ssmtp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 11:47:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/03/25/errors-in-mail-log-from-nagios-check_ssmtp/</guid><description>I got my nagios server banned by fail2ban because of errors in the postfix mail.log log. I know that I can simply whitelist the nagios server but I prefer it working perfectly.
Checking the logs I could see this error repeating itself on each check:
Mar 25 13:01:13 xxx-123 postfix/smtpd[17065]: connect from nagios.example.com[1.2.3.4] Mar 25 13:01:13 xxx-123 postfix/smtpd[17065]: improper command pipelining after QUIT from nagios.example.com[1.2.3.4]: Mar 25 13:01:13 xxx-123 postfix/smtpd[17065]: disconnect from nagios.</description></item><item><title>AIX git SSL woes</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/02/23/aix-git-ssl-woes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 09:27:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/02/23/aix-git-ssl-woes/</guid><description>Oh joy and happiness I have to admin AIX boxes. One of the first things I hit was using git to clone some stuff from github erroring out with:
SSL certificate problem: unable to get local issuer certificate Yep, simple problem, no ssl ca bundle on the system. You can use either the bulldozer solution and have either:
export GIT_SSL_NO_VERIFY=true either:
git config http.sslVerify false ( git config --unset http.sslVerify ) because who cares about MITM attacks especially to deployed software on production servers.</description></item><item><title>Use Vagrant on Windows with Ansible under Cygwin</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/02/04/use-vagrant-on-windows-with-ansible-under-cygwin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 11:24:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/02/04/use-vagrant-on-windows-with-ansible-under-cygwin/</guid><description>If due to some reason you have to run vagrant under windows and plan on using Ansible you will need a couple of wrappers.
ansible-playbook.bat has to be in the Windows PATH;
ansible-winpath-playbook.sh is called by ansible-playbook.bat to change paths from Windows style paths to *nix style paths that ansible under cygwin can understand.</description></item><item><title>Verify SMART details for members of an Intel RST RAID volume</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/10/22/verify-smart-details-for-members-of-an-intel-rst-raid-volume/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 06:02:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/10/22/verify-smart-details-for-members-of-an-intel-rst-raid-volume/</guid><description>Sooo,
Be it because of the BIOS update to a beta or because of my drives but my RAID10 keeps failing. I documented before how to repair such a broken array but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go ahead with it too many times as data corruption is only one step away. Knowing that at least one of the disks has some minor issues (mdadm kicked it out some time ago when the disks were running under linux) I decided to check smart details and only keep only two of the disks in RAID1.</description></item><item><title>Intel RST RAID Non-RAID Disk after BIOS update</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/10/14/intel-rst-raid-non-raid-disk-after-bios-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 06:06:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/10/14/intel-rst-raid-non-raid-disk-after-bios-update/</guid><description>So, having nothing better to do and for no good reason I decided to update my workstation&amp;rsquo;s BIOS to the latest version released by Gigabyte. Since ignoring _the &amp;ldquo;__If it works don&amp;rsquo;t fix it&amp;rdquo; _mantra is always a good idea. Beautiful, after update two of my disks from a four disk RAID10 array were showing as Non-RAID Disk. I had backups but shuffling 2TB+ of data is never fun.
Initial reports were all grim, the Intel RST BIOS does not allow repairing.</description></item><item><title>pfSense home router using the PC Engines APU1D4</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/08/27/pfsense-home-router-using-the-pc-engines-apu1d4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 09:05:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/08/27/pfsense-home-router-using-the-pc-engines-apu1d4/</guid><description>My old home router based on a sandy bridge dual core celeron and a gigabyte motherboard got &amp;ldquo;stolen&amp;rdquo; by my wife to use as a desktop as her old laptop was getting pretty slow.
I ran for a while Tomato on a Cisco E3200 router but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to keep up with my home connection (300 down / 100 up). Even if the router has gigabit ports it was only able to nat at ~100-150Mbit and openvpn was limited to around 10Mbit</description></item><item><title>Brightness keys on Linux Mint for Acer E3-111</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/06/27/brightness-keys-on-linux-mint-for-acer-e3-111/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 09:52:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/06/27/brightness-keys-on-linux-mint-for-acer-e3-111/</guid><description>Enabling brightness control is moderately easy (I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure they worked out of the box on slackware).
Go to codingtony/acer-brightness-linux-acpi and follow the instructions. Change /etc/acpi/events/acer-tm-brightness-down and /etc/acpi/events/acer-tm-brightness-up with the correct events:
event=video/brightnessdown BRTDN 00000087 00000000 and
event=video/brightnessup BRTUP 00000086 00000000 Restart acpid and the shortcuts should start working.</description></item><item><title>Repairing a Husky Hunter after reversing batteries.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/27/repairing-a-husky-hunter-after-reversing-batteries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 06:15:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/27/repairing-a-husky-hunter-after-reversing-batteries/</guid><description>Ok, I did it. For the first time since I can remember I inserted batteries wrongly and reversed polarity. And that in a device I&amp;rsquo;m pretty fond of, and I recently aquired: a Husky Hunter. It was only for a few seconds before I realized my mistake but it was enough, the computer was dead. I tried leaving it overnight with fresh batteries thinking that my mistake instantly depleted the onboard RAM battery (if it&amp;rsquo;s empty a Husky will just play dead until it gets a bit of charge).</description></item><item><title>Migrating Gerrit to Google OAuth from Google OpenID</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/09/migrating-gerrit-to-google-oauth-from-google-openid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 10:17:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/04/09/migrating-gerrit-to-google-oauth-from-google-openid/</guid><description>I expect this post to be obsolete pretty soon, but for now I expect this will help you skip many of the issues and questions I had going forward with upgrading Gerrit and switching to Google OAuth from OpenID.
This post is not exhaustive, I trust that you are familiar with Gerrit if you&amp;rsquo;ve come so far. I am running a gerrit installation that was stuck at v2.10 as all our users used Google OpenID.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi A+ Nixie NTP Clock</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/01/27/raspberry-pi-a-nixie-ntp-clock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 10:30:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/01/27/raspberry-pi-a-nixie-ntp-clock/</guid><description>Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like a Nixie tube based clock. Even my wife loved it. Bonus points if it&amp;rsquo;s very accurate.
I had in my parts box, for a very long time now, the display PCB from an old PH-meter. Old enough that it was done using Rusian 74141 clones - K155ID1 nixie drivers - a lot of logic chips (decade counters, serial latches, etc) and nixie tubes. It was also wired in a way that defied logic.</description></item><item><title>CentOS 6.x misses nobootwait fstab option.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/09/30/centos-6-x-misses-nobootwait-fstab-option/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 06:51:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/09/30/centos-6-x-misses-nobootwait-fstab-option/</guid><description>Recently I added a new storage disk to a cloud server. The issue is that this disk might not always be available at boot time. There is an easy fix for this kind of problems. The nobootwait mount option (like it would show in a fstab entry):
/dev/xvdd1 /storage ext4 defaults,nobootwait 0 0 Note that the fsck order of 0 already ensures that fsck will not hold the boot process by complaining the disk is missing.</description></item><item><title>No album cover art in Symbian ^3 Belle on an E7</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/07/13/no-album-cover-art-in-symbian-3-belle-on-an-e7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 08:31:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/07/13/no-album-cover-art-in-symbian-3-belle-on-an-e7/</guid><description>Sooo, my beloved n900 kicked the bucket and the fine folks at Nokia Romania decided it&amp;rsquo;s not fixable and they replaced it. With an E7. After 6 weeks. Hey Nokia still wondering why you&amp;rsquo;re going down the drain?
I have my music neatly organized and with cover art embeded inside the id3tag. But it won&amp;rsquo;t show up. Actually it showed up for one album out of 15. So I started the hunt to see why.</description></item><item><title>Star Trek S.C.E.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/star-trek-s-c-e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 09:58:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/07/06/star-trek-s-c-e/</guid><description>Have Tech, Will Travel is an anthology collecting the first four books from Pocket Books&amp;rsquo; original eBook series about the Starfleet Corps of Engineers, depicting the missions of a rapid response team of SCE taking place during the 2370s. Several canon characters and concepts were included in the stories, but with new details not mentioned in televised Star Trek of the era.
I have recently finished reading every novel in the Star Trek S.</description></item><item><title>Star Trek 2009</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/06/star-trek-movie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 13:46:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/06/star-trek-movie/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a geek, that means I like Star Trek. That also means that I watched the latest Star Trek movie as soon as it was possible. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have many expectations. Nemesis was a bit of a disapointment, and with everything new and changed I just went to see it. I was pleasently surprised. I found it to be a good movie. A bit different from what I call Star Trek.</description></item><item><title>N800/N810 tablet as a Canon camera remote</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/27/n800n810-tablet-as-a-canon-camera-remote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 09:37:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/27/n800n810-tablet-as-a-canon-camera-remote/</guid><description>This post is also on the talk.maemo.org forum, but I decided to host it here too.
N800 camera remote control I followed a thread regarding the port of gphoto for the Nokia Internet Tablets. Unfortunately gphoto never got me further than list the photos in the camera and then hang and reboot.
Well then I noticed Eostimesync.
Eostimesync is a nice utility that syncs the time of your camera to the time of the n800.</description></item><item><title>Getting sound to work on an old Deskpro EN and Slackware 12.2</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/03/getting-sound-to-work-on-an-old-deskpro-and-slackware-122/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 14:08:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/03/getting-sound-to-work-on-an-old-deskpro-and-slackware-122/</guid><description>I was trying to get rid of the separate sound card in an old Compaq Deskpro En (Pentium III) I use on a jukebox project. Alsa-conf would only detect some weird isa-pnp card that did not work. After searching a bit I found out that the card is an ESS 1869 and is not autodetected. Reading on the alsa website I found that these are the settings that work:
(set in /etc/modprobe.</description></item></channel></rss>