<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lcd on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/lcd/</link><description>Recent content in lcd on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 18:51:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/lcd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing a self pressing button on an Asus VW202SR monitor</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/17/fixing-a-self-pressing-button-on-an-asus-vw202sr-monitor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 18:51:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/17/fixing-a-self-pressing-button-on-an-asus-vw202sr-monitor/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/blog/images/2012/" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/blog/images/2012/IMG_0379.jpg" alt="Broken button Asus Monitor showing Brightness menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, today instead of working I had the pleasure of fixing the monitor 🙂 The monitor is an older Asus VW202 SR that my wife uses connected to the laptop. I tried everything else (power cycling, another signal cable, another computer) but it turns out to be really the button. The issue manifested itself by the brightness setting window appearing and going eventually all the way to 100. First I thought that the button was stuck in the frame but it was safely depressed. That means a broken button on the pcb board. I thought it would be pretty easy to solder a new one in place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bad image quality from HDMI connected PC to Samsung LED LCD</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/04/19/pc-image-quality-bad-on-hdmi-connected-lcd-tv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 12:20:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/04/19/pc-image-quality-bad-on-hdmi-connected-lcd-tv/</guid><description>So, we finally upgraded our old CRT TV to a newer, Full HD Samsung LCD TV (ue37c5000). Since we have a media-center PC the first thing I did was of course hook it up and test a few full hd clips to enjoy the new TV. Everything was nice and well until I switched the tv from the VGA cable I had lying around to a HDMI cable I just bought.</description></item><item><title>4×20 LCD screen with USB interface.</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/31/4x20-lcd-screen-with-usb-interface/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2009 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/31/4x20-lcd-screen-with-usb-interface/</guid><description>Attaching an LCD screen to a pc is a pretty easy job. I am working on a jukebox that I wanted to a screen attached to. Although a HD44780 based LCD can be attached to the parallel port with almost no additional parts I wanted a more flexible solution, and I thought about microcontrollers with usb support. I found a thread here, where all the work is pretty much done. Thank you ch424.</description></item></channel></rss>