<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nas on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/nas/</link><description>Recent content in nas on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 13:05:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/nas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>request_module: runaway loop modprobe binfmt-464c</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/07/request_module-runaway-loop-modprobe-binfmt-464c/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 13:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/07/request_module-runaway-loop-modprobe-binfmt-464c/</guid><description>I added a new disk to my HP N40L and moved the boot disk to another SATA port, which meant reconfiguring lilo. Strange enough after setting everything up I got:
request_module: runaway loop modprobe binfmt-464c right after the kernel loading.
Long story short this message means you are trying to boot a 32bit system with a 64 bit kernel (maybe the other way around will spit something similar). I set the boot parameter wrong and I was actually trying to boot and old 32 bit linux install that was still around on one of the drives in the NAS</description></item><item><title>FreeNAS</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/freenas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 10:32:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/26/freenas/</guid><description>Ok, so I wanted a NAS on my home network. Having just aquired a shabby XPC SK43G that simply refused to work as a htpc (it&amp;rsquo;s original purpose) I decided to set it up as a NAS (Network Attached Storage). I went out and bought a Western Digital Green 1 Tb Sata2 drive. The xpc refused to detect the drive until I set it via jumper as Sata1. I had to search on the Western Digital support pages, as the jumper settings are not documented on the drive itself.</description></item></channel></rss>