<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>perl on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/perl/</link><description>Recent content in perl on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 07:48:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/perl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Search and replace text in many files</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/06/search-and-replace-text-in-many-files/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 07:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/06/search-and-replace-text-in-many-files/</guid><description>This is a handy one liner that searches and replaces text in multiple files. (You can use find for example to run it in multiple folders)
perl -pi -e &amp;#39;s/old_text/new_text/g&amp;#39; *.conf This line replaces old_text with new_text in all the .conf files in the current folder. Of course you can use regular expressions.</description></item><item><title>BackupPC – can’t find Compress::Zlib</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/12/13/backuppc-cant-find-compresszlib/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 07:19:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/12/13/backuppc-cant-find-compresszlib/</guid><description>It all started with an update for perl by our lovely CentOS. After that backuppc complained about Compress::Zlib. I tried installing it from CPAN but it didn&amp;rsquo;t work:
Undefined subroutine &amp;amp;Compress::Zlib::gzopen called One proposed fix was to remove everything Zlib related from the perl folder in /usr/lib. It did work, as CPAN started working but Zlib refused to install due to errors.
I finally stumbled to this fix:
Turns out it&amp;rsquo;s a problem with List::Util.</description></item><item><title>DNS::ZoneParse has an undocumented $ORIGIN</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/11/02/dnszoneparse-has-an-undocumented-origin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 13:29:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/11/02/dnszoneparse-has-an-undocumented-origin/</guid><description>I was working writing a few scripts that should update a DNS zone file on the fly. I decided to use the DNS::ZoneParse perl module for convenience.
The example there is straightforward for changing MX records so I thought modifying it to change an A record should be a piece of cake. Right? Wrong!
For the love of it I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get my code to modify the record in question, it would always delete it.</description></item><item><title>Nagios Grapher fun</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/10/06/nagios-grapher-fun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 15:52:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/10/06/nagios-grapher-fun/</guid><description>I was struggling with Nagios Grapher (or was it nagiosgraph - I tested both) in Slackware 13.1 After installing all dependencies it would still refuse to work. I tracked the problem pretty easy to be related to Perl not being able to load the librrd.so.4 library.
That was funny as I was sure that I did configure, make and make install the latest version. Well, by default, on slackware at least rrdtool installs in /opt !</description></item></channel></rss>