<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>button on Silviu's Blog</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/button/</link><description>Recent content in button on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 18:51:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/button/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing a self pressing button on an Asus VW202SR monitor</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/17/fixing-a-self-pressing-button-on-an-asus-vw202sr-monitor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 18:51:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/17/fixing-a-self-pressing-button-on-an-asus-vw202sr-monitor/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/blog/images/2012/" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/blog/images/2012/IMG_0379.jpg" alt="Broken button Asus Monitor showing Brightness menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, today instead of working I had the pleasure of fixing the monitor 🙂 The monitor is an older Asus VW202 SR that my wife uses connected to the laptop. I tried everything else (power cycling, another signal cable, another computer) but it turns out to be really the button. The issue manifested itself by the brightness setting window appearing and going eventually all the way to 100. First I thought that the button was stuck in the frame but it was safely depressed. That means a broken button on the pcb board. I thought it would be pretty easy to solder a new one in place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Firefox 4 on linux change to one button menu and make it nice and orange</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/04/27/firefox-4-on-linux-change-to-one-button-menu-and-make-it-nice-and-orange/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 05:13:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/04/27/firefox-4-on-linux-change-to-one-button-menu-and-make-it-nice-and-orange/</guid><description>When I upgraded to Firefox 4 on my linux machines I was disappointed to see that the classic menu bar remained. I&amp;rsquo;m not necesarily a fan of the new ribbon interfaces but since I don&amp;rsquo;t use the menu often and so prefer to use the space for something useful, like the tabs.
Reducing the menu bar to a button is easy.
Right click on the menu bar and uncheck Menu bar</description></item><item><title>Put an Online – Offline Yahoo Messenger button on your website</title><link>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/yahoo-messenger-online-now-button-on-your-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 20:46:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/01/16/yahoo-messenger-online-now-button-on-your-website/</guid><description>If you run an online business like an e-store or something similar you might want to show a button showing if your are available to chat via Yahoo Messenger.
This is a fairly easy job to do. All you have to do is to show this code somewhere on your site:
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;ymsgr:sendIM?YOUR_YM_ID&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;#34;http://opi.yahoo.com/online?u=YOUR_YM_ID&amp;amp;m=g&amp;amp;t=1&amp;#34; border=&amp;#34;0&amp;#34; alt=&amp;#34;&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; Remember to replace YOUR_YM_ID with your Yahoo Messenger id and give t a value reflecting the button choice you like:</description></item></channel></rss>