<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tomato on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/tomato/</link><description>Recent content in tomato on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 10:15:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/tomato/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speed-up WAN-LAN speed on the Cisco E3200 using Tomato</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/05/27/speed-up-wan-lan-speed-on-the-cisco-e3200-using-tomato/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 10:15:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/05/27/speed-up-wan-lan-speed-on-the-cisco-e3200-using-tomato/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a really long discussion on bcm_nat and fastnat on the various forums like linksysinfo. The short version of this is:
fastnat and bcm_nat are disabled by default because they break QOS and access restrictions. If you use any of those you&amp;rsquo;re done, you have to choose features or speed or another router. If you, like me, don&amp;rsquo;t use those you can do the following: ssh into your router and try: modprobe bcm_nat than speedtest your connection a few times you should see some improvement.</description></item><item><title>Missing 5Ghz WiFi settings on Cisco E3200 with Tomato Shibby</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/05/20/missing-5ghz-wifi-settings-on-cisco-e3200-with-tomato-shibby/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 06:33:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2015/05/20/missing-5ghz-wifi-settings-on-cisco-e3200-with-tomato-shibby/</guid><description>I followed the instructions and installed Tomat on my Cisco E3200 router without issue. I chose Tomato by Shibby specifically because it supports the 5GHz radio in this particular router model. But woe and behold after I installed the settings were not there, I could only see them for the 2.4GHz WiFi.
Well it turns out instructions are made to be followed, I got curious after install and logged right in, but it turns out you really have to do the last 30-30-30 reset.</description></item></channel></rss>