<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>boot on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/boot/</link><description>Recent content in boot on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 06:51:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/boot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CentOS 6.x misses nobootwait fstab option.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/09/30/centos-6-x-misses-nobootwait-fstab-option/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 06:51:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2013/09/30/centos-6-x-misses-nobootwait-fstab-option/</guid><description>Recently I added a new storage disk to a cloud server. The issue is that this disk might not always be available at boot time. There is an easy fix for this kind of problems. The nobootwait mount option (like it would show in a fstab entry):
/dev/xvdd1 /storage ext4 defaults,nobootwait 0 0 Note that the fsck order of 0 already ensures that fsck will not hold the boot process by complaining the disk is missing.</description></item><item><title>request_module: runaway loop modprobe binfmt-464c</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/07/request_module-runaway-loop-modprobe-binfmt-464c/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 13:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/03/07/request_module-runaway-loop-modprobe-binfmt-464c/</guid><description>I added a new disk to my HP N40L and moved the boot disk to another SATA port, which meant reconfiguring lilo. Strange enough after setting everything up I got:
request_module: runaway loop modprobe binfmt-464c right after the kernel loading.
Long story short this message means you are trying to boot a 32bit system with a 64 bit kernel (maybe the other way around will spit something similar). I set the boot parameter wrong and I was actually trying to boot and old 32 bit linux install that was still around on one of the drives in the NAS</description></item><item><title>Moving a solaris guest from VMWare to Virtualbox</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/16/moving-a-solaris-guest-from-vmware-to-virtualbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 12:01:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2011/06/16/moving-a-solaris-guest-from-vmware-to-virtualbox/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Virtualbox. It&amp;rsquo;s easy, fast and free. Recently I had to revive an older Solaris guest that used to run under vmware, and to set it up to run under Virtualbox. I quickly found out that after the grub screen it enters a reboot loop and nothing seemed to help. I could boot into failsafe and mount the root partition as /a/
Someone suggested that the problem was that vmware had the disk as SCSI (c0t0d0s0) and virtualbox enumerated them as IDE (c0d0s0).</description></item><item><title>Bye, bye, dual boot</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/22/bye-bye-dual-boot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 19:10:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/11/22/bye-bye-dual-boot/</guid><description>Ever since I discovered linux I ran a dual boot system. Linux (usually slackware) + windows (first &amp;lsquo;98 than, as soon as it was available XP). Windows 98 was problematic because it needed frequent reinstalling, pleasently overwriting the boot sector everytime requiring in turn to reinstall lilo.
Than XP solved this problem (not that it didn&amp;rsquo;t quietly overwrite the boot sector) by needing far less frequent reinstalls. When I found out about vmware I was very happy, dual boot seemed a thing of the past.</description></item></channel></rss>