<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wordpress on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/wordpress/</link><description>Recent content in wordpress on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 10:28:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>cbnet Ping Optimizer is killing a site</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/11/cbnet-ping-optimizer-is-killing-a-site/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 10:28:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2012/01/11/cbnet-ping-optimizer-is-killing-a-site/</guid><description>Some wise soul decided many moons ago that installing the aforementioned plugin on a site I host is a great ideea. The wise soul is long gone (admining websites for ngo&amp;rsquo;s as a volunteer is no fun for far too many come and goers:) ) Lately the site was getting more and more sluggish with no apparent reason. I decided to clean a bit the many modules he thought in his wisdom to install.</description></item><item><title>How to add a favicon to your WordPress Blog.</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/09/how-to-add-a-favicon-to-your-wordpress-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/06/09/how-to-add-a-favicon-to-your-wordpress-blog/</guid><description>This was simple:
I used The Gimp to create a file 16 x 16 pixels and saved it as favicon.ico Upload it to the root of your website Added the following to header.php: &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;shortcut icon&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;favicon.ico&amp;#34;&amp;gt; Fast and easy !</description></item><item><title>Wordmobi</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/25/wordmobi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 20:27:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2009/05/25/wordmobi/</guid><description>Another nice little app. Having started this site, I wondered if it is possible to update my blog from my mobile phone. (Nokia E71). Well, WordPress does offer the option to post by email but I didn&amp;rsquo;t find that option too appealing. So a few google searches after I found Scribe and Wordmobi. Both are nice symbian mobile blogging tools. I chose Wordmobi because of the more beefier feature set, suport for the Python 1.</description></item></channel></rss>