<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nagios on Silviu's Blog</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/nagios/</link><description>Recent content in nagios on Silviu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 11:47:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/tags/nagios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Errors in mail.log from nagios check_ssmtp</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/03/25/errors-in-mail-log-from-nagios-check_ssmtp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 11:47:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2016/03/25/errors-in-mail-log-from-nagios-check_ssmtp/</guid><description>I got my nagios server banned by fail2ban because of errors in the postfix mail.log log. I know that I can simply whitelist the nagios server but I prefer it working perfectly.
Checking the logs I could see this error repeating itself on each check:
Mar 25 13:01:13 xxx-123 postfix/smtpd[17065]: connect from nagios.example.com[1.2.3.4] Mar 25 13:01:13 xxx-123 postfix/smtpd[17065]: improper command pipelining after QUIT from nagios.example.com[1.2.3.4]: Mar 25 13:01:13 xxx-123 postfix/smtpd[17065]: disconnect from nagios.</description></item><item><title>Use nagios to track and graph your twitter followers</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/20/use-nagios-to-track-and-graph-your-twitter-followers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 08:23:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/10/20/use-nagios-to-track-and-graph-your-twitter-followers/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Nagios to monitor servers and devices for years now. Lately as an exercise to learn more about nagios I installed a private instance that I use to monitor everything I can think of - from my personal servers to the number of hours we watch TV.
A nice use I found is to monitor the number of followers my twitter bots and personal account have. For that I wrote a custom plugin, available in my small repository of plugins at: https://github.</description></item><item><title>Graph the number of twitter followers using Nagios</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/09/08/graph-the-number-of-twitter-followers-using-nagios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 13:52:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2014/09/08/graph-the-number-of-twitter-followers-using-nagios/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m running a nagios instance on a home machine to monitor and graph all kinds of data. Among them I wanted a graph of the twitter followers of some twitter bots I built.
I needed a script to get this number and for now I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to bother using the API.
The script simply uses curl to get a public http page, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t use the API. Use it and call it like below:</description></item><item><title>Nagios Grapher fun</title><link>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/10/06/nagios-grapher-fun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 15:52:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://silviuvulcan.ro/blog/2010/10/06/nagios-grapher-fun/</guid><description>I was struggling with Nagios Grapher (or was it nagiosgraph - I tested both) in Slackware 13.1 After installing all dependencies it would still refuse to work. I tracked the problem pretty easy to be related to Perl not being able to load the librrd.so.4 library.
That was funny as I was sure that I did configure, make and make install the latest version. Well, by default, on slackware at least rrdtool installs in /opt !</description></item></channel></rss>